Music
音楽
No copyright repentance
著作権の反省はありません
Applause
拍手
I have seen some colleagues in the hospital
病院で何人かの同僚に会ったことがあります
and some of our
そして私たちの一部
former old chief
元老長官
And some senior colleagues
そして何人かの先輩社員も
Thank you very much for coming
ご来場いただき誠にありがとうございました
Our Information Feast Today
今日の情報の饗宴
our today
私たちの今日
Everyone has information
誰もが情報を持っています
Our speech today is given by
今日の私たちのスピーチは、
You Xiaohua Associate Researcher
游孝華副研究員
Research Associate at the Institute of Chemistry
化学研究所助手
tell us
教えて
organic bioelectronics
有機生物電子
Mainly to talk about electronic components
主に電子部品について話します
Combination with biomedicine
バイオ医薬品との組み合わせ
So here I am very briefly
ここで私は非常に簡単に説明します
let me introduce
紹介させてください
Our keynote speaker today is Dr. You Xiaohua
今日の基調講演者は、You Xiaohua 博士です。
he is from
彼の出身は
Graduated from Department of Chemistry, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学化学科卒業
Then to the United States to give birth
その後出産のためアメリカへ
MIT
マサチューセッツ工科大学
Received a doctorate in planning
企画学博士号取得
did some
いくつかやった
After postdoctoral research
博士後研究以後
arrived in singapore
シンガポールに到着しました
senior researcher
主任研究員
Then to Japan
それから日本へ
their physical and chemical
それらの物理的および化学的
RIKEN's so-called RECOM
理研のいわゆるRECOM
Serve as an independent backbone researcher
独立したバックボーン研究者としての役割を果たす
in 2013
2013年に
about 4 years ago
約4年前
just came back
ちょうど今戻ったとこだよ
Institute of Chemistry, Academia Sinica
中央研究院化学研究所
Now working as an associate researcher
現在、准研究員として勤務
so very happy for him
彼にとってとても幸せです
outside
外
coin
コイン
after various experiences
様々な経験を経て
Return to Academia Sinica to serve
中央研究院に戻って奉仕する
PhD research expertise
博士号研究の専門知識
is organic materials chemistry
有機材料化学です
high polymer chemistry
高分子化学
Nanobiotechnology
ナノバイオテクノロジー
biomaterial interface, etc.
生体材料インターフェースなど
The common denominator here is
ここでの共通点は、
this is organic stuff
これはオーガニックなものです
I think there will be Dr.
博士もいると思うよ
can explain to us
私たちに説明してもらえますか
there is carbon in it
中には炭素が入っています
So the structures you see have nothing to do with a single carbon
つまり、あなたが見ている構造は単一の炭素とは何の関係もありません
But his research is now a very emerging direction
しかし、彼の研究は現在、非常に新たな方向性を示しています
It is the combination of electronic components and biomedicine
電子部品と生物医学の組み合わせです
we're going to talk about organic bioelectronics
有機バイオエレクトロニクスについて話します
These two were a very
この二人はとてもよかった
Nor does it mean that in the past in the past, it was a
また、過去において、それがそうであったという意味でもありません。
Separate and independent fields
個別の独立したフィールド
two separate domains
2 つの別々のドメイン
But in recent decades
しかしここ数十年で
Slowly we know that many things have become a combination of cross-fields
多くのことがクロスフィールドの組み合わせになっていることが徐々にわかってきます
there will be some new developments
いくつかの新しい展開があるでしょう
So in English, you can see that this is Oberonic Power Electronics
英語では、これが Oberonic Power Electronics であることがわかります。
so a very emerging field
非常に新興の分野です
It's not like there's been a lot of research in this area
この分野についてはあまり研究が進んでいるわけではない
Some of the leading positions above
上記の主要な役職の一部
he has recently
彼は最近
In last year 2016
昨年2016年には
Won our Academy's Young Scholar Research Writing Award
アカデミーの若手研究者リサーチライティング賞を受賞
Also won the Mr. Wu Dayou Memorial Award from the Ministry of Science and Technology
科学技術省呉大佑氏記念賞も受賞
This is to reward young researchers
若手研究者の表彰のためです
the most important award
最も重要な賞
In the Chinese Chemical Society also took
中国化学会でも取り上げられた
Contact Seven Chemistry Awards
Seven Chemistry Awards へのお問い合わせ
Accept the invitation of the Japanese Judiciary Corporation Gaofeng Sub-society
日本司法法人高峰分会の招待に応じる
International Young Scientist Award
国際若手科学者賞
behind
後ろ
in that year
その年に
Before going to college, it used to be
大学に入る前はそうでした
Well, Han Yao Titi used to be
そう、ハン・ヤオ・ティティはかつて
International Olympia gold medal for high school students
国際オリンピア高校生金メダル
gold medal in chemistry
化学で金メダル
So he's doing really well in medical studies and research.
つまり、彼は医学の研究や研究で非常に良い成績を収めています。
but do the math
でも数える
A representative of our young and promising Academia Sinica
若くて将来有望な中央研究院の代表者
but
しかし
His speech today is mainly in this aspect
今日の彼のスピーチは主にこの側面に関するものです
It is what we have seen in this introduction
それがこの紹介文で見たことです
These turned out to be two different fields
これらは 2 つの異なるフィールドであることが判明しました
Because in the past in electronic components
なぜなら、昔は電子部品で
Let's take a look inside your own iPhone
自分のiPhoneの内部を覗いてみましょう
All those components are inorganic
これらの成分はすべて無機物です
Because there are many semiconductor
半導体が多いので
or other metals
または他の金属
make that link in it
その中にそのリンクを作成します
It's almost an inorganic world
ほとんど無機質な世界です
What about organic chemistry?
有機化学はどうでしょうか？
We know from some of the more traditional areas of the original
私たちはオリジナルのより伝統的な分野のいくつかを知っています
Also slowly develop this way
このようにゆっくりと成長することも
So we probably also heard
だから私たちもおそらく聞いたでしょう
in the news or in newspapers and magazines
ニュースや新聞や雑誌で
I have heard that organic light-emitting diodes
有機発光ダイオードって聞いたことがありますが、
or organic transistor
有機トランジスタとか
and organic solar cells
および有機太陽電池
so in these
それで、これらの中で
in electronic components
電子部品で
also give us a new direction
私たちに新しい方向性も与えてください
So in two very distinct areas like this
このように 2 つの非常に異なる領域で
We're going to put it together now
これから組み立てていきます
so today
それで今日
I don't do too much now
今はあまりやりすぎない
wasting too much of everyone's time
みんなの時間を無駄にしすぎている
So Dr. Yau will tell us
そこでヤウ博士が教えてくれます。
These two are how we connect
この2つは私たちがつながる方法です
After connecting
接続後
it will take us in some new directions
それは私たちに新しい方向性を与えてくれるでしょう
have what
何がある
make us feel very hopeful
私たちにとても希望を感じさせます
Then there are some directions for great development in the future
そして、将来の大きな発展へのいくつかの方向性があります
so we welcome our speakers today
それでは、今日はスピーカーをお迎えします
Dr. You Xiuhua
游秀華博士
Thank you, Vice President Zhou, for your introduction
周副社長、ご紹介いただきありがとうございます
I would also like to thank you all for coming here today.
本日もお越しいただきまして誠にありがとうございます。
listen to me
私の話を聞いて下さい
Introduce this new field
この新しい分野を紹介します
then i think
それから私は思います
Because actually when I was preparing
というのも、実は準備をしていたときに
I'm actually a little apprehensive
実は少し不安なのですが
because i don't know
知らないから
there are two things
二つのことがあります
that's because
それは
The main international homestay is
主な海外ホームステイは、
Host Dang Er told me this
ダン・アーホストが私にこう言いました
speeches can have a wide range
スピーチの範囲は広い
the audience is very wide
聴衆は非常に幅広いです
In addition, it seems that there is a live broadcast now
また、現在生放送も行われているようです
in this way
この上
so i'm not sure who will hear
だから誰が聞くかわからない
At least my son told me before I went out
少なくとも息子は私が出かける前に言いました
He will watch my live
彼は私のライブを見てくれるでしょう
So if I'm going to say something he can understand
だからもし私が何か言おうとしたら彼は理解できるだろう
it might be a little hard work
少し大変な作業かもしれない
my son is ten years old
私の息子は10歳です
But I want to be with today I take this opportunity
でも今日は一緒にいたい この機会に
I think I'll try to be able to
できるように努力してみようと思います
Hope to understand
ご理解いただけると幸いです
I will introduce this new field
この新しい分野を紹介します
Then I may spend more time on the introduction
そうすれば紹介にもっと時間を費やせるかもしれません
I hope that everyone can understand this field
皆さんにもこの分野を理解していただけると幸いです
have a little concept
ちょっとしたコンセプトがある
My premise is that you probably haven't heard of this field
前提として、あなたはおそらくこの分野について聞いたことがないでしょう
So if you've heard the field
この分野の話を聞いたことがあるなら
or know something
または何かを知っています
That
それか
i'm sorry over there
そこはごめんなさい
Because there may be some things for people
人には何かあるかもしれないから
may be simpler
もっと簡単かもしれない
But I think in such an information imagination
でもそんな情報の想像力の中で私は思う
I would like to share with you
皆さんと共有したいと思います
Start this series of stories from the beginning
この一連のストーリーを最初から始める
that's also very
那也非常
Also very grateful to the Central News Bureau
也非常感謝中央新聞局
let me in 2014
2014年にさせてください
Able to return to Taiwan to serve
台湾に戻って奉仕することができる
Then the continuation is
次にやるべきことは、
Serving the country like this
こうやって国に奉仕するんだ
then i
その後私は
just
ただ
Vice President Zhou has already mentioned
周副主席はすでに言及した
that is
あれは
traditionally speaking
伝統的に言えば
naturally
当然
the greatest one
最偉大的一個
What about the creation?
創作に関してはどうでしょうか？
that is
あれは
various creatures
いろいろな生き物
all kinds of creatures
あらゆる種類の生き物
you see it's a creature
あなたはそれが生き物であることがわかります
that human
あの人間
Actually humans say
実際人間はこう言うんだよ
Truth is the greatest creation
真実は最も偉大な創造物である
in the most recent
一番近いところで
throughout the 20th century
20世紀を通じて
The main creation is
主な創作物は、
so-called electronic components
いわゆる電子部品
These two things are actually
この２つは実は
On the face of it
表面的には
It seems irrelevant
無関係のようです
because they have many
彼らはたくさん持っているから
difference in nature
性質の違い
there are many in
にはたくさんあります
especially on scale
特に規模に関しては
you can know
あなたは知ることができます
people
人
at least one person is
少なくとも1人は
150 cm
150cm
to 200 cm
200cmまで
Most of them fall in this range
ほとんどがこの範囲に収まります
An electronic component is called seven nanometers according to the latest manufacturing process of Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company.
台湾積体電路製造会社の最新の製造プロセスによれば、電子部品は7ナノメートルと呼ばれます。
It is a whole scale is completely different
全体のスケールが全く違います
It will have a scale mismatch
スケールの不一致が発生します
Then from our material point of view
次に、物質的な観点から見ると、
You can feel that in terms of materials, human beings are a soft substance
物質的には人間は柔らかい物質であることが実感できる
Your body is not a hard gang you are not a steel seat substance
あなたの体は硬いギャングではありません、あなたは鋼鉄のシート物質ではありません
But most electronic components are made of hard materials
しかし、ほとんどの電子部品は硬い材料でできています
Contains fine materials containing a wide variety of so-called III-V elements
いわゆるIII-V族元素を幅広く含む微細な物質が含まれています
There are even materials containing various oxides
さまざまな酸化物を含む材料もあります
These are hard materials
これらは硬い素材です
And if we analyze more deeply
さらに深く分析してみると
Humans are basically organic matter
人間は基本的には有機物です
All wafers are mostly inorganic substances
すべてのウェーハはほとんどが無機物です
The cost of organic matter and its main component is carbon
有機物のコストとその主成分は炭素です
and not only carbon
カーボンだけではありません
And the most important thing we talk about in terms of opportunities is
機会に関して私たちが話す最も重要なことは、
Carbon composed of co-driving chains
共駆動チェーンから構成されるカーボン
Promise matter is mainly formed from various accumulations of atoms
約束物質は主にさまざまな原子の集合体から形成されます
pile up into a hard material
積み重なって硬い物質になる
so what
だから何
The two substances are very different in nature
2 つの物質は性質が大きく異なります
then let's think again
それからもう一度考えてみましょう
It's a question of conductivity
導電率の問題です
everyone knows just
ただ誰もが知っている
recently my son
最近私の息子
i mentioned my son again
私はもう一度息子のことを言いました
You may hear me mention my son all the time
私がいつも息子のことを話しているのが聞こえるかもしれません
Because in fact, I often make metaphors
実際、私は比喩をよくするので、
Then my son just happened to be in the fourth grade of elementary school recently.
すると息子はたまたま最近小学4年生になりました。
Just about to learn electricity
電気の勉強をしているところです
Just in the fourth grade of elementary school
ちょうど小学4年生の頃
Immediately the fourth class will learn electricity
さっそく4年生は電気の学習をします
because i want to teach him
彼に教えたいから
so i know
だから私は知っています
So he's just about to learn electricity
それで彼はたまたま電気を学んだだけです
but the first thing
でも最初のこと
We all know that the human body conducts electricity.
人間の体が電気を通すことは誰もが知っています。
Conductivity of the human body
人体の導電率
But with the conduction of electronic components
しかし、電子部品の伝導により、
it's a completely different probability
全く違う確率です
The conduction of the human body is a very complex system
人体の伝導は非常に複雑なシステムです
in comparison
比較において
Conductivity of electronic components
電子部品の導電性
nothing but electrons
電子以外の何ものでもない
or electric
または電気
Move on the circuit, this I think most people
サーキットで移動する、これはほとんどの人がそう思う
will have a little bit of basic concepts
基本的な概念を少し説明します
electronics or circuits
電子回路とか電子回路とか
There is a basic move on the original road with a collective
集団での本来の道での基本的な動きがある
So, it's two first, the material itself that conducts electricity
では、まず 2 つ目は、電気を通す素材そのものです。
not the same
同じではありません
In this complex system, I will explain in a moment
この複雑なシステムについては、すぐに説明します
Let me explain to you in detail, it mainly comes from the transmission of some ions
詳しく説明しますと、主にイオンの透過によって起こります。
Include
含む
uh gai ion
ああ、ガイイオン
Contains false ions , Contains that ion
偽イオンを含む、そのイオンを含む
And even these have some so-called neurotransmitters
そしてこれらにもいわゆる神経伝達物質が含まれています
New-On Transmitter
New-On 送信機
What does acetylcholine contain in these
アセチルコリンには何が含まれていますか
substance
物質
that, the last is
それ、最後は
The human body is a dynamic system
人間の体はダイナミックなシステムです
The so-called dynamic means
いわゆる動的手段
We grow up from small to large, your scale is always getting bigger
私たちは小さなものから大きなものへと成長し、あなたの規模は常に大きくなっています
None of us are born with such a big scale
私たちの誰も、これほど大きなスケールを持って生まれてきません
So it's a dynamic system
つまりダイナミックなシステムなのです
And then, when you're getting older, you're going to age
そして、年を重ねると、老化していきます。
So the whole system will also enter a decay state
したがって、システム全体も衰退状態に入るでしょう
It includes Agent, including some reasons for aging
老化の理由を含むエージェントが含まれます
that this
これは
The chip itself is a very steady state
チップ自体は非常に安定した状態です
We make semiconductor components
私たちは半導体部品を製造しています
the most important thing is to say
最も重要なことは言うことです
How many times can you use this semiconductor
この半導体は何回使用できますか
how many times can switch
何回切り替えられるか
can switch can
切り替えることができます
Applicable
該当する
how long can your life be
あなたの人生はどれくらい長くなりますか
the best
最高の
Semiconductor life is infinite
半導体の寿命は無限大
because they encapsulated it
彼らはそれをカプセル化したので
In fact, it can be used for a long time
実は長く使えるんです
So these two things are actually different in nature.
したがって、これら 2 つは実際には性質が異なります。
then we
それから私たち
But
しかし
certainly
そうです
When the wisdom of nature meets the wisdom of man
自然の知恵と人間の知恵が出会うとき
Finally we want to do one thing
最後にやりたいことが 1 つあります
just put it together
それを組み合わせるだけです
that when combined
それを組み合わせると
there will be one
一つあるだろう
Materially
物質的に
a difference in material
素材の違い
so how do we tie it together
それで、それをどのように結び付けますか
This is what I want to share with you today
今日皆さんと共有したいのはこれです
is how to use
使い方です
so-called organic conductive substances
いわゆる有機導電性物質
to make such a combination
このような組み合わせを作るには
certainly
そうです
what will happen in the future
将来何が起こるでしょうか
we are not sure
私たちにはわかりません
organic
有機
What electronic components can cause
電子部品が引き起こす可能性のあるもの
future but
将来だけど
Sometimes we're not sure, but Hollywood is sure
時々確信が持てないこともあるが、ハリウッドは確かだ
The film industry is very powerful, he will tell us what will happen next
映画業界は非常に強力です、彼は次に何が起こるかを教えてくれるでしょう
For example, when your people can start to control
たとえば、従業員がコントロールできるようになったとき
When using chips to control external machinery
チップを使用して外部機器を制御する場合
you just...
あなたはただ...
You may appear like RoboCop, RoboCop
あなたはロボコップ、ロボコップのように見えるかもしれません
It's a possibility that you can control machines outside with just your brain
脳だけで屋外の機械を制御できる可能性
Turn the signal of the nerves of your human brain into the signal of an electronic component
人間の脳の神経信号を電子部品の信号に変換します。
send out , then go to control the machine
それを送信して、マシンを制御します
Of course, if one day machines want to control people
もちろん、いつか機械が人間をコントロールしたいと思ったら
Then the possible situation will be like Magix
その場合、起こり得る状況はMagixのようなものになります
We humans become mechanical batteries
私たち人間は機械の電池になります
Like a hacker character, say that people in the future don't need you to think
ハッカーのキャラクターのように、未来の人々は考える必要がないと言います。
Mechanical thinking ability is stronger than yours, I didn't believe it before
機械的思考能力は君より強い、今まで信じられなかった
but since the defeat of afghanistan this...
しかし、アフガニスタンの敗北以来、これは...
We actually ran into some colleagues from the Information Office last time.
実は前回、情報局の同僚に偶然会ったのです。
He said we're all rethinking who gets to make the decisions
彼は、誰が決定を下すのかを私たち全員が再考していると言いました
so this is an interesting question that I think
これは興味深い質問だと思います
Is it a machine controller or a human controlling the machine?
それは機械のコントローラーでしょうか、それとも機械を制御する人間でしょうか?
Of course we want humans to control the machines
もちろん人間が機械を制御することを望んでいます
No matter which scenario needs an interface
どのシナリオでもインターフェースが必要
How do you transfer energy out of the body
どうやってエネルギーを体外に移動させるのですか
How to make the so-called electrical signals and these biological signals of your body
いわゆる電気信号や体の生物学的信号をどのように生成するか
produces an appropriate conversion
適切な変換を生成します
This is the ultimate goal of organic bioelectronics
これが有機バイオエレクトロニクスの究極の目標です
We want to have a very efficient conversion
非常に効率的な変換を実現したい
There is a clear conversion
明らかな変換があります
OK, let me mention it a little more
わかりました、もう少し言及しましょう
In fact, everyone, I have been interested in this research very early.
実は皆さん、私はこの研究にかなり早くから興味を持っていました。
I've always found it funny since I probably started in graduate school
おそらく大学院に通い始めた頃から、ずっと面白いと思っていました
Because everyone knows, of course, on the one hand, we are from Taiwan
もちろん誰もが知っているので、一方では私たちは台湾出身です
Taiwan is the Kingdom of Semiconductors
台湾は半導体王国です
Taiwan is electronic components
台湾は電子部品です
most famous country
最も有名な国
Every one of my classmates is in TSMC
私のクラスメートは全員TSMCにいます
Then each of them left TSMC
その後、彼らはそれぞれTSMCを去りました
Because they all went to start a company
みんな会社を立ち上げようとしていたから
So everyone has been to TSMC
みんなTSMCに行ったことあるよ
Each one leaves TSMC
それぞれがTSMCを離れる
But Taiwan's electronic components
でも台湾の電子部品は
With such a strong strength
こんなに強い力で
Now it has also entered the so-called Hon Hai of electronic components
今では電子部品のいわゆる鴻海にも参入した
very early on i started thinking
かなり早い段階で私は考え始めました
Where is the next South China Sea?
次の南シナ海はどこですか？
just say we certainly can't
絶対に無理だと言ってください
Just start over and restart a stove
最初からやり直してストーブを再起動してください
Where might the next South China Sea for electronic components be?
電子部品の次の南シナ海はどこになるでしょうか?
so i always feel like saying
だからいつも言いたくなるんだ
Then shall we just
それでは、そのままにしましょうか
Let's say you made a nice transistor
素晴らしいトランジスタを作ったとしましょう
You can put the transistor
トランジスタを入れることもできます
Just insert it directly into the human body to control the human body
人体に直接挿入するだけで人体をコントロール
what kind of difficulties it will encounter
どのような困難に遭遇するか
In fact, when I first entered the Ph.
実際、私が初めて博士課程に入学したとき、
i had this idea
私はこのアイデアを持っていました
but i always feel
でも私はいつも感じています
My boss won't approve the first one
私の上司は最初の提案を承認しません
The second one seems a bit risky
2つ目はちょっと危険な気がする
I can't find anyone to plug, so I can't plug myself
接続できる人が見つからないので、自分自身で接続することもできません
Right, so we want to say
そう、だから私たちが言いたいのは、
I was thinking about something like this, but
こんなことを考えていたのですが、
After ten years, twenty years of thinking
10年、20年考えた末に
We found that the two middle actually
実際には真ん中の2つが
there is a difference
違いがあります
You can imagine, the traditional electronic components, what kind of characteristics it has
従来の電子部品がどのような特徴を持っているかを想像することができます。
Traditional electronic components are made of hard materials
従来の電子部品は硬い材料で作られています
All of these materials are required to be stable in the air
これらの材料はすべて空気中で安定であることが必要です
Of course, many electronic components have to be unstable in the air
もちろん、多くの電子部品は空気中では不安定でなければなりません
But we use a very precise method to package it up
しかし、私たちはそれをパッケージ化するために非常に正確な方法を使用しました
package it up
それをパッケージ化する
So there are many good raw packaging factories in Taiwan
台湾には優れた生包装工場がたくさんあります
Then after packaging, the life of these electronic components can be very long
パッケージング後、これらの電子部品の寿命は非常に長くなります。
Then most of the applied one
それから、適用されたもののほとんどは
For one application, the so-called process status is the so-called
あるアプリケーションの場合、いわゆるプロセス ステータスは、
CO, is a vapor deposition
COは蒸着です
is a chemical vapor deposition
化学気相成長法です
It is a way to use, to use the frame rate
フレームレートを使用する方法です
Use the gas frame method to go
ガスフレーム方式を使用して移動します
then what we need
それから私たちに必要なものは
What we need is that this system is very robust
私たちに必要なのは、このシステムが非常に堅牢であることです
For example, if you want to buy a TV
たとえば、テレビを買いたいとすると、
you bought a computer
あなたはコンピュータを買いました
Of course you wish you could use it for the rest of your life
もちろん一生使い続けて欲しいですよね
Although your manufacturer may not want you to use it for a lifetime
メーカーはそれを生涯使用することを望んでいないかもしれませんが、
But the person you buy expects him to use for a lifetime
しかし、あなたが買う人は一生使うことを期待しています。
Then
それから
at last
最後
This may be a bit more controversial
これはもう少し物議を醸すかもしれません
but actually
でも実は
for
ために
In terms of toxicity
毒性という点では
Our requirement is actually full minimum
私たちの要件は実際には完全な最小値です
Just don't be toxic to the environment
ただ環境に有害にはならないでください
Don't be toxic to the environment when you shoot this thing
これを撃つときは環境に有害にならないでください
Then the material used is actually
さて、実際に使用される材料は、
We all know the materials used to make semiconductors
半導体の製造に使用される材料は誰もが知っています。
Impossible not poisonous
不可能ではない毒
just use light folic acid
軽い葉酸だけを使用してください
Everyone is free to check
誰でも自由にチェックできる
What kind of poison is folic acid
葉酸とはどんな毒なのか
What kind of poison is the Buddha's gas used?
仏陀のガスにはどのような毒が使われているのでしょうか？
It is quite toxic
かなり有毒です
but of course we can
でももちろんできます
We apply sophisticated
洗練された
mechanical manipulation
機械的操作
mechanical engineering techniques
機械工学技術
We can maintain it in an environment
環境で維持できる
don't let it poison
毒にしないでください
but essentially use
しかし基本的には使用します
is poisonous
有毒です
but
しかし
Because this program is very good
この番組はとても良い番組なので、
Then lead to so much output value in Taiwan
そうすれば台湾での生産額が非常に大きくなる
Of course it also led us
もちろんそれは私たちも導いてくれました
I didn't see many young people at the scene, but
現場では若い人はあまり見かけませんでしたが、
Just heard the news that
というニュースを聞いたばかりです
Nowadays, young people are more and more fond of
最近は若い人にも人気が増えていますね
don't miss Dr.
博士をお見逃しなく。
Because it is very profitable to go to TSMC
TSMCに行くととてもお得なので
but of course
しかし、もちろん
Taiwan's economy has made considerable contributions
台湾経済は多大な貢献をしている
I don't deny it at all
全然否定しませんよ
but i can only say
でも言えることは
Such a process is
そのようなプロセスは、
He does have a different way of thinking and an idea
彼は違う考え方やアイデアを持っています
But when anything you come into contact with living organisms
しかし、何かが生き物と接触すると、
Let's see what it might need
何が必要なのか見てみましょう
first in bioelectronics
バイオエレクトロニクスで初めて
Generally speaking, what we want is soft matter
一般的に言えば、私たちが欲しいのはソフトマターです
why soft matter
なぜソフトマターなのか
I often make a metaphor for everyone
私はよくみんなを比喩します
Of course, I always feel that my metaphor is very bad.
もちろん、私はいつも自分の比喩が非常に悪いと感じています。
But let's just listen
でもちょっと聞いてみましょう
Just a question for everyone
皆さんに質問です
do you like to sleep or
寝るのが好きですか、それとも
Hard bed or soft bed?
硬いベッドですか、それとも柔らかいベッドですか？
Most people like to sleep on a soft Tuanwang bed
ほとんどの人は柔らかいトゥアンワンベッドで寝るのが好きです
Hard bed but wouldn't you want to sleep on a plank
硬いベッドだけど板の上で寝てみませんか？
I'm not saying
言ってないよ
For organisms
生物にとって
Thin wafers are not just boards
薄いウェーハは単なる基板ではありません
And it's a cold marble floor
そしてそれは冷たい大理石の床です
very bad sleep
非常に悪い睡眠
So any biochip
つまり、どんなバイオチップでも
If you're going to have a meeting with a creature
生き物と出会うなら
It actually prefers soft matter
実は柔らかいものを好むのです
just a bit soft
ほんの少し柔らかい
Whether it is hydrogel, Hydrogel
ハイドロゲルかどうか、ハイドロゲルかどうか
or how
あるいはどうやって
what it likes is a soft substance
好きなものは柔らかい物です
In addition to being stable in the air, it
空中でも安定しているだけでなく、
The most important thing is to be stable in the water
最も重要なことは水中で安定していることです
Because the most abundant of all living organisms is water
すべての生物の中で最も豊富に存在するのは水だからです
You have to have water stability
水の安定性が必要です
Okay, let's think about the stability of the water again.
さて、水の安定性についてもう一度考えてみましょう。
Words on the stability of our water
水の安定性についての言葉
This is for traditional e-liquid
従来のリキッドの場合
indeed a challenge
本当に挑戦です
right
右
We often see all kinds of people on the Internet
私たちはインターネット上でさまざまな人々をよく見かけます。
The PO article said that the iPhone got water accidentally today
PO の記事では、今日 iPhone に誤って水がかかってしまったと書かれていました
then it's over
それで終わりです
right so let's think about it
そうだ、それでは考えてみましょう
The main thing is your stability in the water
重要なのは水中での安定性です
and you made this
そしてあなたがこれを作りました
The entire process is best made with easy
プロセス全体は簡単に行うのが最適です
because it is easy to make
簡単に作れるので
You can use many polymer materials
多くのポリマー材料を使用できます
So my polymer materials cannot be stacked by vaporization
したがって、私のポリマー材料は気化によって積み重ねることができません
must come with water
水と一緒に来なければなりません
must be handled with easy images
簡単なイメージで処理する必要がある
and then the other one is
そしてもう一つは
in bioelectronics
バイオエレクトロニクスで
If your material is too balanced or too durable
素材のバランスが良すぎる、または耐久性が高すぎる場合
It's not necessarily a good thing
それは必ずしも良いことではありません
Because sometimes we want this material to be biodegradable
場合によっては、この素材を生分解性であることが必要になるためです
That is to say, when it has completed its mission
つまり、使命を終えたとき
organisms will automatically decompose it
微生物が自動的に分解してくれる
In this way, the compounding of nature and your body will be less
このようにして、自然とあなたの体の混合は少なくなります
So the last thing that matters most is
最後に最も重要なことは、
This toxicity is in bioelectronics
この毒性はバイオエレクトロニクスにあります
is a very large concentration because you have to be in direct contact with your body
体に直接触れる必要があるため、濃度が非常に高くなります。
From a scientific point of view
科学的な観点から
He has to touch your body
彼はあなたの体に触れなければなりません
So we have to have very, very low toxicity
したがって、毒性を非常に低くする必要があります
from an economic point of view
経済的な観点から
Because you have to pass the FDA
FDAを通過する必要があるため
you have to go through regulation
規制を通過しなければならない
You have to go through all the legal institutions to circumvent
回避するにはすべての法的機関を通過する必要があります
You have to have compliance biotoxicity
コンプライアンスを遵守する必要があります 生物毒性
Otherwise you have no way to go public
そうでなければ公開する方法がない
you can't turn it into a product
それを製品にすることはできません
You can't generate market value
市場価値を生み出せない
this is all in
これですべてです
so-called once inside the biological element
いわゆる生物学的要素の中に一度入った
Problems that traditional electronic components must face
従来の電子部品が直面しなければならない問題
So let me do a simple analysis with you first
それでは、まず簡単な分析をさせてください
I hope everyone has a clear statement
全員が明確な意見を持っていることを願っています
Traditional Inorganic Materials
伝統的な無機材料
maybe need an up
おそらくアップが必要です
need an upgrade need an upgrade
アップグレードが必要です アップグレードが必要です
for use in bioelectronics
バイオエレクトロニクス用途向け
That
それか
the opposite
反対
in chemistry
化学で
Because I still study chemistry
私はまだ化学を勉強しているので
Although many people think that I don’t seem to be doing chemistry recently
最近化学やってないみたいだと思われている人も多いですが
But my former university teacher is here
でも、私の元大学の先生がここにいます
so i have to say i still study chemistry
だから私はまだ化学を勉強していると言わざるを得ません
So traditional chemistry
つまり伝統的な化学
Usually, there are two types of materials
素材は大きく分けて2種類あります
organic materials
有機材料
Inorganic materials
一類叫無機材料
that organic material was stigmatized for a while
その有機材料はしばらく非難されていました
Now it's more advanced
今ではさらに進化しています
Because organic food is more expensive
オーガニック食品は値段が高いので
So the word organic has become very advanced again
オーガニックという言葉が再び非常に高度なものになりました
for a while organic wasn't great
しばらくの間、オーガニックは素晴らしいものではありませんでした
that's it
それでおしまい
so in terms of dialogue
対話という意味では
The definition of organic for us is very simple
私たちにとってのオーガニックの定義はとてもシンプルです
Organic is a structure based on carbon
有機物は炭素をベースにした構造です
then formed
その後結成されました
Focus on co-driving
共同運転に注力
some compounds or molecules that form
形成されるいくつかの化合物または分子
Inorganic is everything except carbon
無機物とは炭素以外のものを指します
is inorganic
無機質です
so but
だから、でも
Traditionally, everyone knows organic, and what everyone knows best about organic is plastic
伝統的に、オーガニックはオーガニックであること、そしてオーガニックについて誰もが最もよく知っているのはプラスチックであることは誰もが知っています。
We usually deal with plastic, plastic, think about it
私たちは普段、プラスチック、プラスチックを扱っています、考えてみてください
Thinking about it from the brain, plastic, plastic does not conduct electricity
脳で考えると、プラスチック、プラスチックは電気を通さない
right , we learn anything
そう、私たちは何でも学びます
Whether it is middle school or high school, we will be the first to say that plastics do not conduct electricity
中学校でも高校でも、プラスチックは電気を通さないと最初に言います。
Plastic is a flying conductor
プラスチックは空飛ぶ導体です
Traditionally, the decomposition of organic and inorganic
従来、有機物と無機物の分解は、
organics are flying conductors, then inorganic compounds
有機物は空飛ぶ導体であり、次に無機化合物です
There are many with metallic luster and high conductivity
金属光沢があり、導電性が高いものが多い
but
しかし
all the rules of chemistry
化学のすべてのルール
are all
全てです
formulated to be broken
壊れるように作られている
As we enter the millennium, the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 2000
ミレニアムに入ると、2000 年のノーベル化学賞
Most importantly to these three gentlemen
この三人の紳士にとって最も重要なことは
Professor Allen Peecker,Professor Allen McDermott
アレン・ピーカー教授、アレン・マクダーモット教授
and Professor Hidesu Shirakawa from Japan, the first two are American professors
日本の教授と白川秀氏、最初の2人はアメリカ人の教授です。
them
彼ら
discover something together
一緒に何かを発見する
plastic conducts electricity
プラスチックは電気を通す
We can make conductive plastic
導電性プラスチックが作れます
Well, I think today I'm going to take a little time to tell you about this story.
さて、今日はこの話をするために少し時間を割いてみようと思いました。
Because the research I did for this story was
なぜなら、この物語のために私が行った調査は、
it's the whole beginning
それはすべての始まりです
This whole new field of
この全く新しい分野の
a bad wound
ひどい傷
That's why my field as a whole started booming
それが私の分野全体が活況を呈し始めた理由です
Whether it is organic electronics
有機エレクトロニクスかどうか
no matter how
どんなに
Next Organic Bioelectronics
次の有機バイオエレクトロニクス
I can only say
ただ言えるのは
All our research is standing
私たちの研究はすべて継続中です
Seniors stand on the shoulders of these giants to see the world
高齢者は巨人の肩の上に立って世界を見る
we didn't start from scratch
私たちはゼロから始めたわけではありません
We are all the result of following others
私たちは皆、他人に従った結果です
So we've taken a look for you
そこで私たちはあなたのことを調べてみました
All Nobel said that the Nobel words of two thousand years were awarded to these three
ノーベルは皆、二千年のノーベルの言葉はこの三人に授与されたと述べた
Mainly found to say
主に言うことがわかった
There is a kind of conductive polymer called
と呼ばれる一種の導電性高分子があります。
From whitening to complete, it is conductive plastic
ホワイトニングから完成まで、導電性プラスチックです
plastic is conductive
プラスチックは導電性がある
that's why
それが理由です
I will give you some simple analysis
簡単な分析をさせていただきます
today so far
今日はこれまでのところ
actually
実際
I'm quite proud
とても誇りに思います
But so far I haven't put any chemistry room
でも今のところ化学室は設置していない
He knows that those who study chemistry will definitely get a bachelor of chemistry
彼は、化学を勉強すれば必ず化学の学士号を取得できることを知っています。
I'm sorry, I'm going to put Chem now.
ごめんなさい、今から Chem を入れます。
Before that, let me tell you
その前に言っておきますが、
Because I was still a student when I was able to speak for two thousand years
二千年話せる頃はまだ学生だったから
so in two thousand zero this should be two thousand zero
したがって、2000 ゼロでは、これは 2000 ゼロになるはずです
In 2003 or 2003 in a
2003年か2003年に
Annual Meeting of the American Chemical Society
アメリカ化学会年次総会
i was lucky to hear
聞けて幸運でした
Lecture by Professor Ellen McDermott
エレン・マクダーモット教授による講演
And he's actually a really nice guy
そして彼は実際にとてもいい人です
He's also a guy who likes to show off very much
彼はとても自己顕示欲の強い男でもあります
So he put his Nobel medal over there for everyone to take pictures
それで彼はノーベルメダルをそこに置き、みんなが写真を撮れるようにした
So you can take pictures if you want
なので、必要に応じて写真を撮ることもできます
Of course I think it should be true
もちろんそれが真実であるべきだと思う
Shouldn't be shipping
発送すべきではない
So we based on a student's instinct
そこで私たちは学生の直感に基づいて
Just have something to take care of
ただ気をつけるべきことがある
You must punch in the photo
写真にパンチを入れなければなりません
no
いいえ
Although I didn't check in
チェックインしていないのに
But there must have been such a thing as punching cards in those days.
しかし、当時はパンチカードがあったはずです。
Then you can see
そうすればわかります
This is a photo of the Nobel Prize for two thousand years
これは二千年ぶりのノーベル賞の写真です
Although at that time everyone can realize
その時は誰もが感じますが
The camera at that time was 2 megapixels
当時のカメラは200万画素
So this is a bit unclear
それで、これは少し不明瞭です
OK, let's tell you a little bit about this story
さて、この話について少し話しましょう
This story is actually a
この物語は実は、
To me it's actually a pretty
私にとってそれは実際に美しいものです
pretty inspiring story
かなり感動的な話
That is to say, when we are doing scientific research in chemical research
つまり、化学研究で科学的な研究をしているとき、
In fact, this story came from a complete mistake.
実はこの話は完全な間違いから生まれました。
I will introduce this error
このエラーを紹介します
Then we start with crude oil
それから原油から始めます
Everyone knows polymers
誰もが知っているポリマー
that is, plastic
つまりプラスチックです
most famous of plastics
プラスチックの中で最も有名な
This is what is called Juyixi
これが居西と呼ばれるものです
Taiwan also produces a lot
台湾もたくさん生産しています
Juyixi
居西
In chemistry, we do it by taking Yixi
化学では、Yixi を使用してそれを行います。
this monomer
このモノマー
make it a
それをする
polyyixi
ポリイシ
That
それか
Such a process, of course
もちろんそのようなプロセス
Yixi is better now than his brother
イーシーは今では兄よりも優れています
quite a bit
かなり
Because his brother's name is Bingxi
兄の名前はビンシーだから
Bingxi is quite notorious now.
冰渓は今ではかなり悪名高い。
Because it's notorious since Ma Kaohsiung bombed
馬高雄の爆撃以来悪名高いから
What about his gas?
彼のガスはどうですか？
Polymers can then become Polymers
ポリマーはポリマーになることができます
Then if we use some
次に、いくつかを使用すると、
Catholist
カトリック教徒
with some coarser
もう少し粗いもので
Especially do what we call Cigernata Catis
特にCigernata Catisと呼ばれるものをやります
Of course Cigernata Catis is another Nobel Prize
もちろん、シゲルナータ・カティスもノーベル賞です
This is the 1963 Nobel Prize
これは1963年のノーベル賞です
someone found out
誰かが見つけた
How to use lizards to make high value
トカゲを使って高価値を生み出す方法
very tall great polyether material
非常に背の高い優れたポリエーテル素材
these two
この二つ
Cigur discovered this together with Nata
シガーとナタは一緒にこれを発見しました
because of its strong economic value
経済的価値が高いため
So that's why later
だから後ほど
Plastic has become a very dominant material in the world
プラスチックは世界で非常に支配的な素材となっています
Because we have discovered many new ways in the village
私たちは村でたくさんの新しい方法を発見したからです
Capable of making very high value polylizards
非常に価値の高いポリトカゲを作成できる
that in chemistry in science
科学における化学のこと
people are quick to think
人々は考えるのが早い
So what can Cigernata Catis start doing
では、Cigernata Catis は何を始められるでしょうか
So in 1955 to 1960 can start
つまり 1955 年から 1960 年にかけて始まる可能性があります
use
用
one of lizards
トカゲの一つ
a compound of a brother
兄弟の化合物
lizard
トカゲ
want to aggregate it
集計したい
poly-lizard
ポリトカゲ
see if there is
あるかどうか見てください
something like this happens
このようなことが起こります
That 195.12.6 says
195.12.6 にはこう書かれています
many people send
多くの人が送ってくれる
some people reported that
何人かが報告した
According to lack of discovery
発見の欠如によると
But what they found missing was a
しかし、彼らが足りないと感じたのは、
black powder
黒い粉
That
それか
I just mentioned three professors
先ほど三人の教授の話をしましたが、
Professor Na Shirakawa
白川奈教授
At that time he had just started his research career
当時彼は研究者としてのキャリアを始めたばかりでした
he
他
just want to try this experiment
この実験を試してみたいだけです
to learn about this experiment
この実験について学ぶために
what about this time
今回はどうですか
some day
いつか
He was with a Korean student
彼は韓国人の学生と一緒でした
found to say
言うことがわかった
Eh
えー
he reacts the same way
彼も同じように反応する
he found out that
彼はそれを知った
Eh
えー
how did he get one
彼はどうやってそれを手に入れたのか
A film with a metallic luster
金属光沢のあるフィルム
what happened
どうしたの
so what
だから何
words in the lab
研究室での言葉
i think we
私たちはそう思う
presence if
もし存在するなら
probably many are
おそらく多くの人がそうだろう
the ancestors of the Central Academy
中央院的先輩
I may also have domestic scholars
国内の学者もいるかもしれない
we see this problem
私たちはこの問題を認識しています
Of course we're going back and checking our lab notes
もちろん、戻って研究ノートを確認します
see bottom
一番下を参照
What went wrong
何が悪かったのか
they found one thing
彼らは一つのことを見つけた
Oops, they made the most of chemists
おっと、彼らは化学者を最大限に活用しました
worst mistake
最悪の間違い
It's just that they miscalculated the equivalent
それは彼らが同等の計算を間違えただけです
That is to say, when they write, they put
つまり、彼らが書くとき、
It is possible to put minimolar mini
ミニモル・ミニを入れることが可能
change, forget, mm
変更する、忘れる、mm
millet
キビ
forgot
忘れた
So they used a thousand times
それで彼らは何千回も使いました
Equivalent
同等
Chemicals
化学薬品
Use a very large amount of deodorant
消臭剤を大量に使用する
So the reaction is very fast
なので反応がとても早いです
It only takes a minute or two for the film to form
膜が形成されるまでにかかる時間はわずか 1 ～ 2 分です
very fast
とても早い
This is completely different from previous reports
これまでのレポートとは全く異なります
so of course
だからもちろん
What happens next is even more special
次に起こることはさらに特別です
generally speaking
一般的に言えば
Sometimes we find that
時々私たちはそれを見つける
especially
特に
We don't see too many students on site
現場ではあまり多くの学生を見かけません
sometimes, but maybe
時々、でも多分
There are students live
学生が住んでいます
Sometimes students see something wrong
時々、学生は何かが間違っていることに気づきます
I feel like, ah, what's wrong?
ああ、どうしたの？という感じです。
wash him off , don ' t tell the teacher
彼を洗い流してください、先生には言わないでください
Otherwise, maybe the teachers will scold me
そうしないと先生に叱られるかも知れません
in this way
この上
But something is wrong
でも何かが間違っている
Sometimes, will give you some new
時々、あなたに新しいものを与えます
Often many scientific discoveries
多くの場合、多くの科学的発見が
in such an error
このようなエラーで
produce a beautiful result
美しい結果を生み出す
So when they found this metallic luster
それで彼らがこの金属光沢を見つけたとき
Actually quite excited
実際かなり興奮してる
just found out
たった今わかった
Hey, what the hell is this thing?
おい、これは一体何なんだ？
just at this time
ちょうどこの時に
He later discovered this in 1967
彼は後に 1967 年にこれを発見しました
until 1975
1975年まで
the second of these
そのうちの2番目
Professor Nadelman
乃德爾門教授
he went to japan
彼は日本に行きました
At that time, Professor Baichuan Yingxiu was at Dongqing Public Health University
当時、白川英秀教授は東清公衆衛生大学にいた
when he visited
彼が訪れたとき
Professor Baichuan Yingxiu is discussing the result
結果について議論するBaichuan Yingxiu教授
he is very excited
彼はとても興奮しています
He immediately invited Professor Baichuan to come in 1977
彼はすぐに白川教授を 1977 年に来るよう招待しました。
Excuse me
すみません
Eh, very wrong
えー、とても間違っています
1977 time to
1977年まで
arrive
到着
Uh Penn
ああ、ペン
when they were at the university of penn
彼らがペン大学にいたとき
to do
すること
Profession
職業
That's why they systematically discovered
だからこそ彼らは体系的に発見したのです
turn out to be
であった
what he synthesized
彼が合成したもの
According to lack
不足に応じて
might be one of these
これらのいずれかかもしれません
biology of a molecule
分子の生物学
But the structure of this molecule is not the source of the conduction
しかし、この分子の構造は伝導の源ではありません。
but like a semiconductor
でも半導体みたいに
When I apply some compound in the middle go
真ん中にコンパウンドを塗ると
so-called defects
いわゆる欠陥
let these all the orbitals of this molecule
この分子のすべての軌道をこれらにしましょう
When the consensus molecular orbitals create defects
コンセンサス分子軌道が欠陥を生成する場合
it produces like metal
それは金属のように生成します
The so-called electronic belt and driving belt
いわゆる電子ベルトと駆動ベルト
The so-called Valence Band
所謂的Valence Band
A concept with Conduction Band
伝導帯のコンセプト
Then they learned that
それから彼らはそれを学びました
Where does the conductivity of atoms come from?
原子の導電性はどこから来るのでしょうか?
According to the Shirakawa Sonic System
白河ソニックシステムによる
It's my own autobiography
それは私自身の自伝です
They were in the lab that day
その日彼らは研究室にいました
once
一旦
When the time comes their show
時間が来たら彼らのショー
Show gas once down after
ガスを一度下げた後に表示
he noticed that
彼はそれに気づいた
Conductivity increased by a million-fold
導電率が100万倍に増加
Because the equipment at that time was very bad
当時の設備は非常に貧弱だったので、
Just no Auto Switch
オートスイッチがないだけ
So you have to use the Menu Switch
したがって、メニュースイッチを使用する必要があります
What will be the problem if the current is suddenly too high?
電流が突然高くなりすぎると何が問題になりますか?
The machine will burn
機械が燃えてしまいます
So they took one of their
それで彼らはそのうちの1つを手に取りました
4.0 pog is burned
4.0pogが燃えます
but anyway
とにかく
Burned a 4.0pog in exchange for a Nobel Prize
ノーベル賞と引き換えに4.0pogを燃やした
i think it's worth it
価値があると思います
ok
Ok
So here is a story for you
そこで、ここにあなたのための物語があります
Of course this story is for us
もちろんこの物語は私たちのためのものです
To me, the inspiration is that
私にとってインスピレーションとなるのは、
In fact, sometimes this thing actually
実際、時々このことは実際に
that time
その時
And their first paper was published in a
そして彼らの最初の論文は、
A very specialized journal in chemistry is called CAMCO
化学の非常に専門的な雑誌はCAMCOと呼ばれます
Now many people want to talk about publishing Science
今、多くの人がサイエンスの出版について話したいと考えています
Nature
自然
They are not posting Science
彼らは科学を投稿していません
They actually put a lot of effort into these a lot
彼らは実際にこれらのことに多くの努力を費やしています
Very basic and Fundamental
非常に基本的で基本的なこと
very basic science
非常に基礎的な科学
Get some results that no one else thought of
誰も思いつかなかった結果を得る
I believe everyone in Xuehua knows that
雪華の皆さんはそれを知っていると思います
traditional organic and inorganic
伝統的な有機と無機
A so-called boundary is broken
いわゆる境界線が壊れた
the first time was in
初めて
18 years old
18歳
The so-called Ulava
所謂的Ulava
can make green acid
緑色の酸を作ることができる
hydrocyanic acid
青酸
when it becomes urea
尿素になると
This is the so-called low boundary between organic and inorganic is broken
これは、有機と無機の間のいわゆる低い境界が壊れた状態です。
after
後
When we found Fyrocyn
フィロシンを見つけたとき
When I found Tie Erwu Wan
ティ・エルウー・ワンを見つけたとき
electricity is broken
電気が壊れています
Then this can be said to be broken again for the third time.
そうなると、これはまた三度目に壊れたと言えます。
Because we used to think that only metals can conduct electricity
なぜなら、私たちは金属だけが電気を通すと考えていたからです。
Now it is not
今はそうではありません
Planned
計画済み
piece of plastic
プラスチック片
it also conducts electricity
電気も通します
and it will have different properties
そしてそれは異なる特性を持つでしょう
because it is soft matter
柔らかい物質なので
is a soft substance that conducts electricity
電気を通す柔らかい物質です
OK
OK
Then I would like to take this opportunity to mention a little bit.
それでは、この機会に少し触れさせていただきたいと思います。
Because I just mentioned that Vice President Zhou
なぜなら、先ほど周副主席のことを言いました。
i am in japan
私は日本にいます
The School of Physics and Chemistry has worked in the institute for six years
物理化学学部はこの研究所で6年間働いています
Actually, I know some of Shirakawa's students
実は私は白川先生の生徒を何人か知っています。
In fact, Professor Shirakawa Hidesu is a
実は、白川秀秀先生は、
very funny chemist
とても面白い化学者
I tell you his story
彼の話をします
thinking about private matters
プライベートなことを考える
because i think i will
そうなると思うから
talk about everything
すべてについて話す
I hope everyone can take the blame for this
みんながこの責任を負えることを願っています
That is to say, Professor Hideso Shirakawa
つまり、白川秀宗先生です。
actually a
実際には
I think, the title behind this is not written by any magazine, nor is it written by a weekly magazine. I think
このタイトルは雑誌が書いたものでも週刊誌が書いたものでもないと思います。
He's an underrated trans scientist.
彼は過小評価されているトランス科学者です。
Because he was born in Tokyo in 1936
1936年東京生まれだから
He received a Ph.D. from Tokyo Institute of Technology, Tokyo Institute of Technology in 1966
1966年東京工業大学大学院博士課程修了、博士号取得。
In 1967, it was discovered that lack of metal luster
金属光沢が欠けていることが1967年に発見されました。
In 1976, he was a visiting researcher at the University of Pennsylvania. In 1977, they discovered that the conductive graph can be increased by 1 million times.
1976 年にペンシルベニア大学の客員研究員となり、1977 年に導電性グラフが 100 万倍に増加できることを発見しました。
But no one cares about this result
でも誰もこの結果なんて気にしてないよ
In 1979, under the Japanese system
1979年、日本の制度のもとで
Generally speaking, wherever you get your Ph.D., you will find ways to become an assistant professor in that laboratory
一般的に、どこで博士号を取得しても、その研究室の助教授になる道は見つかります。
Associate Professor , Becoming Professor of Politics
准教授、政治学教授に就任
But because people don't think his result is nothing
でも人々は彼の結果が何もないとは思っていないから
So he was forced to move from Tokyo Institute of Technology to Takesa University, where he became a professor
そこで彼は東京工業大学から武佐大学に移ることを余儀なくされ、そこで教授となった。
Then in March 2000
そして2000年3月に
You can count it, that is, he is 65 years old, and he is going to retire
数えてもいいでしょう、つまり彼は 65 歳で、退職する予定です
pension
年金
he
他
The Japanese system is like this
日本の制度はこんな感じ
Maybe they are all Japanese friends
たぶん彼らは全員日本人の友達です
Well done if you call retirement
退職と言うならよくやった
Like Vice President Zhou
周副総統のように
You can change to another place to continue your career
キャリアを続けるために別の場所に転職することも可能
Although you have to retire where you were
元いた場所で引退しなければなりませんが、
but you may have to be able to go to the next place
でも次の場所に行けないといけないかもしれない
but
しかし
no one wants him
誰も彼を望んでいない
Enough University March 2003
十分な大学 2003 年 3 月
he is basically
彼は基本的に
Retire naked
裸で引退する
I don't mean to quit naked
裸で辞めるつもりはない
He took his pension
彼は年金を受け取った
but
しかし
did not continue him
彼は続けなかった
He said my research career was over
彼は私の研究者としてのキャリアは終わったと言いました
And then more ironically
そしてさらに皮肉なことに
In October 2001 he won the Nobel Prize
2001 年 10 月に彼はノーベル賞を受賞しました
all the schools start looking for him
すべての学校が彼を探し始める
his students told me
彼の生徒たちが私に言いました
he told them
彼は彼らに言った
Back then you didn't want me
あの頃、あなたは私を必要としませんでした
I don't want you now
今はあなたはいらない
He continues to retreat naked
彼は裸で後退し続ける
he just stays on
彼はただそこに留まる
stay in
にとどまる
He actually did something
彼は実際に何かをしました
because i know him
私は彼を知っているので
i know him students tell me
私は彼を知っています 学生が私に言う
their science museum in japan
日本の科学博物館
There are experiments to teach children to do conductive polymers
子供たちに導電性ポリマーの作り方を教える実験がある
He will personally explain to them
彼は個人的に彼らに説明します
what is the principle of this experiment
この実験の原理は何ですか
He is a
彼は
Even if he was bigger than the professor last year
たとえ彼が去年の教授より大きかったとしても
The Nobel Prize-winning animal that died because of cells
ノーベル賞獣は細胞のせい
He also came out to criticize
彼も批判に出てきた
Today's young people don't know how to do mental science
今の若者は精神科学のやり方を知らない
In fact, he has great enthusiasm for this science.
実際、彼はこの科学に対して多大な熱意を持っています。
But when
でもいつ
whether in japan
日本にいるかどうか
Actually in Japan
実は日本でも
He is also a very underrated word also called
彼はまた、非常に過小評価されている言葉でもあります
of all nobel prizes
すべてのノーベル賞のうち
No one particularly admires him
誰も特に彼を尊敬していない
but
しかし
I can only say he really
彼は本当にとしか言えない
I to me he's really a very serious scientist
私にとって彼は本当にとても真面目な科学者です
There are also many serious scientists in the Central Academy
中央アカデミーには真面目な科学者もたくさんいます
that is
あれは
we found a phenomenon
私たちはある現象を見つけました
we are willing to pursue
私たちは喜んで追求します
Science is supposed to be a pursuit
科学は追求するものであるはずだ
Sometimes you don't care what's going on outside
外で何が起こっているかなんて気にしないこともある
or what others have to say
または他の人の意見
we just keep going
私たちはただ進み続けます
so he
彼は
i feel in
私は感じています
take advantage of
活用する
Usually I don't know how to talk about this
通常、このことについてどう話せばいいのかわかりません
but
しかし
Since it is a knowledge experiment
知識実験なので
I thought I'd share it with you
それをあなたと共有したいと思いました
this is me
これが私です
he treats me personally
彼は私を個人的に扱ってくれます
all one
全部一つ
Enlightenment and inspiration
啓発とインスピレーション
That is to say
つまり
I think sometimes scientific research does not need to think too much
科学研究はあまり深く考える必要がないこともあると思います
what can be used
何が使えるのか
can it be used
使えるでしょうか
All he actually found was an attitude
彼が実際に見つけたのは態度だけだった
He actually didn't do it
彼は実際にはそれをしませんでした
what's behind
後ろに何があるのか
organic light emitting diode
有機発光ダイオード
Organic Electron
有機電子
he didn't do it
彼はそれをしませんでした
The only thing he did was understand
彼がした唯一のことは理解することだった
conductive polymer
導電高分子
why conduct electricity
なぜ電気を通すのか
He spent a lot of effort to understand this matter
彼はこの問題を理解するために多大な努力を費やした
Then I think this is a very important one
それから、これはとても重要なことだと思います
Fundamental Science的improvement
基礎科学の向上
so why
なぜ
2000 will not speak
2000年には話せません
Although he is not the first to make a conductive polymer
彼は導電性ポリマーを初めて作ったわけではありませんが、
but he
でも彼は
Share this Price with two other scientists
この価格を他の 2 人の科学者と共有します
ok
Ok
then i will continue
それでは続けます
Compare
比較
academic part
学術的な部分
That is to say
つまり
Of course, we first started from this so-called
もちろん、最初はこのいわゆる
The shortage begins
巨缺開始
but the same structure
でも同じ構造
Chemists are smart
化学者は賢い
use it in various ways
いろいろな方法で使ってください
to cause this
これを引き起こすために
so-called co-double bond
いわゆる共二重結合
So if you have any questions
ご質問がございましたら
To have two double bonds is
二重結合が2つあるということは、
you two
あなた方二人
One sword is called double sword, one sword is called single sword
一本の剣を双剣、一本の剣を片剣といいます。
That is to say, you must be two swords and one sword
つまり二刀一刀でなければならない。
Two swords and one sword, two swords and one sword, lined up like this
二本の剣と一本の剣、二本の剣と一本の剣、こうやって並べてます
We found many different
たくさんの異なるものを見つけました
There are cases where compounds contain the so-called
化合物にいわゆる次のものが含まれる場合があります。
Jupiluo, two swords and one sword
ジュピルオ、二刀と一刀
two swords one sword two swords one sword two swords one sword
二つの剣 一つの剣 二つの剣 一つの剣 二つの剣 一つの剣
Or Jusunfen, two swords and one sword
あるいはジュスンフェン、二刀と一刀
Two swords and one sword, even combined swords
二刀と一刀、合体刀も
A lot of different things are also being thought about, such as
などなど、いろいろなことも考えられています。
polyanoling, it also conducts electricity
ポリアノール、電気も通す
There are even some more complex
さらに複雑なものもあります
Contains the so-called aggregated to... aggregated to the missing
いわゆる集約されたものが含まれています... 欠落しているものに集約されています
If you get together, they will also conduct electricity
集まれば電気も通る
These materials are actually very important, because some of them conduct electricity
これらの材料は電気を通すものもあるため、実際には非常に重要です。
Some are now being used as optoelectronic materials
一部は現在オプトエレクトロニクス材料として使用されています
These materials, in varying amounts, allow the field to flourish
これらの物質は、さまざまな量で畑の繁栄を可能にします。
This is in chemical science
これは化学科学の話です
As for the application
申請に関しては
I believe everyone
私はみんなを信じます
More or less have heard of these applications
多かれ少なかれ、これらのアプリケーションについて聞いたことがあるでしょう
Of course, the most famous of these is the
もちろん、その中で最も有名なのは、
OLED stands for Organic Light Emitting Diode
OLEDは有機発光ダイオードの略です
many of you now
今、皆さんの多くが
mobile phone backplane
携帯電話のバックプレーン
We all claim to be the backplane of OLED
私たちは皆、自分が OLED のバックプレーンであると主張しています
even this one
これでも
this is
これは
sorry this is korean
ごめんなさい、これは韓国人です
Because Taiwan has not yet made it
台湾はまだ出来てないから
This is Korean and this is Samsung
こちらは韓国製、こちらはサムスン製です
OLED to Think TV
OLEDでテレビを考える
there is also
もあります
Maybe it's made so-called organic
いわゆるオーガニックで作られているのかもしれません
Transistor
トランジスタ
That
それか
We all know that the biggest difference between Internet material and obligation quality is
インターネットのコンテンツと義務の品質の最大の違いは次のとおりであることは誰もが知っています。
We are now bendable transistors
私たちは今、曲げられるトランジスタです
This transistor can be bent
このトランジスタは曲げることができます
Transistors that become so-called late
いわゆる遅くなってしまったトランジスタ
Then this is a solar panel of the late style
それではこちらが後期型のソーラーパネルです
Organic Solar Panels
有機ソーラーパネル
even if you put the transistor
トランジスタを入れても
make one with a creature
生き物と一つを作る
This is more like outside
こちらの方が外っぽいですね
So we're not really bioelectronics
つまり、私たちは実際にはバイオエレクトロニクスではないのです
Because bioelectronics our way is inside the body
私たちのバイオエレクトロニクスは体内にあるので
But in vitro it can also be designed as
しかし、in vitro では次のように設計することもできます。
like
好き
An artificial hand like this
こんな義手
This is made by Professor Somya of the University of Tokyo
これは東京大学の宗谷教授が作ったものです。
These are mainly currently
これらは現在主に
market or company
市場または会社
Prototypes that can already be seen
すでに見られるプロトタイプ
When the employed person in Central was in chemistry
セントラルに就職した人が化学だった頃
we also do
私たちもそうします
Many of my colleagues are also doing this kind of research.
私の同僚の多くもこの種の研究を行っています。
did a pretty good job too
かなり良い仕事もしました
of course
もちろん
My interest is sometimes
私の興味は時々
most of the time
ほとんどの時間
Not the same as others
他の人と同じではない
It was when my classmates were going to TSMC
それは私のクラスメートがTSMCに行くときでした
I choose to study chemistry
私は化学を勉強することにしました
so of course they are doing
もちろん彼らはやっています
this when i look at
これを見ると
A lot of people do this when Invipend
Invipend のときに多くの人がこれを行います
solar cell what?
太陽電池って何？
but i think
しかし、私は思います
I don't know because maybe I'm more afraid of competition
分からない、もしかしたら競争の方が怖いからかもしれない
I think I might not win even in competition
競争しても勝てないかも知れません
in this way
この上
or I feel tired of competing
あるいは競争することに疲れた
So we just make a new one that is
したがって、新しいものを作成するだけです。
I want to know what he is biologically
彼が生物学的に何なのか知りたい
how do we combine
どのように組み合わせるか
how to design
どのようにデザインするか
How do we make this phenomenon available in living organisms
この現象を生物内でどのように利用できるようにするか
Can
できる
non-stop application
ノンストップアプリケーション
right
右
So let me introduce one more
そこでもう一つ紹介させてください
the most important thing is to say
最も重要なことは言うことです
just mentioned one thing
一つだけ言及しました
Even living organisms have electricity
生き物にも電気はある
But with
しかし、
The electricity of electronic components is not the same as electricity
電子部品の電気は電気とは違います
What about the electricity in living organisms?
生物の電気はどうなるのでしょうか？
this is the nervous system
これは神経系です
nervous system
神経系
This is what I cut out from a paper
紙から切り抜いたのがこれです
so more complicated
とても複雑です
But the main thing is that there is this so-called
しかし、重要なことは、これはいわゆる
Bandwide section
Bandwide的部分
There is a part called Axon
軸索と呼ばれる部分があります
what is so called
いわゆる何ですか
the most important
最も重要な
I think this simplifies it
これで簡略化できると思います
explain to you
あなたに説明してください
the most important thing is to say
最も重要なことは言うことです
it is done by some
それは一部の人によって行われています
easy one
簡単なもの
concentration difference
濃度差
produces a so-called
いわゆる
Potential difference
電位差
this is called
これは呼ばれます
Usually we call it Axon Potential
通常、私たちはそれを軸索電位と呼びます
kinetic potential
運動電位
That is, it uses some of the
つまり、次の一部を使用します。
ion channel
イオンチャネル
Contains the ion channel
イオンチャネルが含まれています
or pseudo ion channel
または擬似イオンチャネル
when using it to send out ion channels
イオンチャネルを送信するために使用する場合
The resulting potential difference
結果として生じる電位差
between different cells
異なる細胞間
This potential difference can be transmitted continuously
この電位差は継続的に伝達されます
and then at the end
そして最後に
when it utilizes this so-called Excel tail-end
このいわゆる Excel テールエンドを利用する場合
it utilizes this tail
この尻尾を利用するのです
This potential can stimulate it
この可能性がそれを刺激する可能性があります
to secrete so-called neurotransmitters
いわゆる神経伝達物質を分泌する
to the next neuron source
次のニューロンソースへ
So one of the most important things is
したがって、最も重要なことの 1 つは、
source of the signal
信号源
In fact, these ions and these
実際、これらのイオンとこれら
neurotransmitter
神経伝達物質
Now here comes the problem
ここで問題が発生します
our electric substance
私たちの電気物質
The signal transmitted is from electronic and electric
送信される信号は電子的および電気的なものです
Neurogenic is derived from ionic
Neurogenic はイオンに由来します
What about these two things?
この２点についてはどうでしょうか？
to talk
話す
how to talk
話し方
at this time
現時点では
conductive polymer
導電高分子
another feature
別の機能
when we designed
私たちがデザインしたとき
don't know
わかりません
but
しかし
It's amazing in a
それは素晴らしいです
Such a one with a plan
そんな計画のある方
Naturally, there will be such characteristics
当然そういう特徴もあるでしょう
this is where we go now
ここが今行くところです
let's take a closer look
もっと詳しく見てみましょう
If a conductive polymer
導電性ポリマーの場合
It is a structure like this
こんな構造です
That might be a molecular structure like this
こういう分子構造なのかもしれません
when it
それがいつ
when current is applied to it
電流を流すと
That is, when you give it an electrical signal
つまり、電気信号を与えると、
This compound molecule
この化合物分子は
The polymer itself will be oxidized
ポリマー自体が酸化してしまう
produces an electrochemical reaction
電気化学反応を起こす
That is to say, the chemical system
つまり、化学系は
It was great
よかった
can combine electricity and chemistry
電気と化学を組み合わせることができる
medium
媒介
It produces an electrochemical reaction after
後に電気化学反応を起こします。
Because the entire conductor must maintain electrical neutrality
導体全体が電気的中性を維持する必要があるため
So it must start from
したがって、それはから開始する必要があります
Easy to absorb ions in
イオンを吸収しやすい
that is, naturally
つまり当然のことながら
It takes this electrical signal
この電気信号を受け取ります
becomes an ion signal
イオン信号になる
And how much electricity do you add
そしてどれくらいの電気を追加しますか
How many ions does it absorb
どれくらいのイオンを吸収しますか
These two will produce a linear relationship
これら 2 つは直線的な関係を生み出します
That is, conductive organic conductive materials
つまり、導電性有機導電材料
itself is a good way to connect electrons and ions
それ自体が電子とイオンを結び付ける良い方法です
A tool that can do a signal conversion
信号変換を行うことができるツール
That's why we can quickly
だからこそ、すぐに
Putting conductive polymers on their own can do things like
導電性ポリマーを単独で配置すると、次のようなことができます。
And in this process, there is actually a side effect
そして、このプロセスでは実際に副作用があります
It's because you sucked in the ions
イオンを吸い込んだからだよ
So this thing gets bigger
それで、これは大きくなります
If the volume becomes larger, you can feel it
音量が大きくなると実感できる
it will produce if you stick it on a board
ボードに貼り付けると生成されます
As it gets bigger, the board bends
大きくなると板が曲がってしまう
You restore it again, and the board comes back
もう一度復元するとボードが元に戻ります
So we can design something like
したがって、次のようなものを設計できます
Kinetic components, Kinetic components
運動コンポーネント、運動コンポーネント
For example, the film below
例えば、下の映画は、
It is actually a fixed state
実際は固定状態です
One piece is the dynamic state of this conductive polymer
ワンピースはこの導電性ポリマーの動的状態です
So you can tell when I give it a Pulse
だから私がパルスを与えるとわかるよ
It can produce a vibration phenomenon
振動現象を引き起こす可能性があります
produce such a movement phenomenon
このような運動現象を引き起こす
This can be used as a
これは として使えます、その時は参加させていただきました
actuator or a more popular name
アクチュエーターまたはより一般的な名前
we call it artificial muscle
私たちはそれを人工筋肉と呼んでいます
like your muscles
あなたの筋肉のように
can move around like this
このように移動できます
can move around
動き回れる
Just call it artificial muscle
人工筋肉と呼んでください
ok
Ok
so i want to share
だから共有したいのです
So such organic bioelectronic components
このような有機バイオエレクトロニクスコンポーネント
on application
申請上
There are many possible potential
潜在的な可能性はたくさんあります
Of course, I like this field very much.
もちろん、私はこの分野がとても好きです。
I also believe that this field has considerable value in the industry
また、この分野は業界において非常に価値のある分野であると信じています
Especially in Taiwan so big
特に台湾は大きいので
Such a powerful electronic component
このような強力な電子コンポーネント
With the support of an electronics factory
エレクトロニクス工場の協力を得て
With such good technology
こんなに良い技術があるのに
This direction is actually for the electronics factory
実はこの方向はエレクトロニクス工場向けです
It's not that hard to get into the horizontal ditch
横溝に入るのはそれほど難しくない
Maybe even sometimes I think it's better than medicine
薬より気分が良くなることもあるかもしれない
Biological technology may be even easier
生物技術はさらに簡単になるかもしれない
because we have mastered ourselves
なぜなら私たちは自分自身を克服したからです
It is the technology of making this electronic component
この電子部品を作る技術です
The main generation may have bio-detectors
主要世代には生体検出器が搭載されている可能性がある
or a bioelectrode
または生体電極
Or there are some so-called neurological
あるいは、いわゆる神経学的なものもあります。
stimulating electrodes
刺激電極
that's sorry for the rest
残りはごめんなさい
I don't know how to turn
向きを変える方法がわかりません
so i use english
だから私は英語を使います
the so-called
いわゆる
It's getting married
結婚するんだよ
so-called artificial muscles
いわゆる人工筋肉
I just gave you an example
例を挙げただけです
or so-called
またはいわゆる
Medical Bionics
メディカルバイオニクス
just like that
まさにそのように
like robocop
ロボコップみたいに
how do i get my brain waves
脳波を取得するにはどうすればよいですか
can control me outside
外で私をコントロールできる
The movement of this biomimetic system
この生体模倣システムの動き
even
平
There are still many
まだたくさんあります
Includes Electronic Skin
電子スキンを含む
is how on your skin
あなたの肌はどうですか
started to put on
履き始めた
Install the detector
検出器を設置する
So when your hand moves
だから手が動くと
This receptor naturally has a signal
この受容体は自然に信号を持っています
you can learn
あなたが学ぶことができます
You can send signals automatically
自動的に信号を送信できます
even
平
I have new ones recently
最近新しいのが入ってます
one is someone put
1つは誰かが置いたものです
such a wafer
そのようなチップ
implanted in your nervous system
神経系に埋め込まれている
Then use a phenomenon of biological
次に、生物学的現象を利用します。
when an electric signal is emitted
電気信号が発せられると
The nervous system stimulates the immune system
神経系が免疫系を刺激する
Immunotherapy can begin
免疫療法が始められる
this you on the internet
これはインターネット上のあなたです
can be found
見つけることができます
I
私
How to Harness Organic Bioelectronic Components
有機バイオエレクトロニクスコンポーネントを活用する方法
as a medicine
薬として
Use it to stimulate your body to release
身体の解放を刺激するために使用します。
Chemicals your body is supposed to release
体が放出すべき化学物質
Diseases that cause your body can be cured
あなたの体の原因となる病気は治る可能性があります
Some people are doing these studies
こういう研究をしている人もいる
very responsible of course
もちろん非常に責任があります
I have to tell everyone here
ここにいる皆さんに伝えなければなりません
Well, it's just a matter of being a member.
まあ、それは会員になるだけの問題です。
actually
実際
Organic Electronic Components
有機電子部品
enough trouble
十分なトラブル
Because organic electronic components contain chemical
有機電子部品には化学物質が含まれているため、
physics engineering
物理工学
Well, if you think about it, organic bioelectronic components
そうですね、よく考えてみると、有機バイオエレクトロニクス部品
Includes Chemistry, Physics, Engineering, Biology and Medicine
化学、物理学、工学、生物学、医学が含まれます
So all of you have to come together
だから皆さんも集まらなければなりません
This is totally transpsychic research
これは完全に超精神的な研究です
you are unlikely to do it alone
あなたはそれを一人でやる可能性は低いです
You have to have a lot of like minded people
同じような考えを持つ人がたくさんいるはずだ
would like to share this
これを共有したいと思います
Such research goals, research ideals
このような研究目標、研究理念
to be able to do
できるように
I'm lucky enough to always have
私は幸運なことにいつも持っています
People are willing to cooperate with me
人々は喜んで私に協力してくれる
so we
だから私たちは
I actually basically do stuff
私は実際に基本的に何かをやっています
see you later
また後で
Actually the most basic one
実は最も基本的なもの
maybe say yes
たぶん「はい」と言うでしょう
You can say it is the most critical one on the component
これはコンポーネント上で最も重要なものであると言えます。
But it's actually very simple
しかし、実際はとてもシンプルです
All I do is say how to control
私はコントロール方法を言うだけです
this electronic component
この電子部品
an interface with the organism
生体とのインターフェース
How to make this interface ensure that
このインターフェースを確実に作成する方法
electrical and biological signals
電気信号と生体信号
able to deliver the complete
完全なものを納品できる
won't lose
負けません
using chemistry and materials
化学と材料を使って
this is what i'm doing
これが私がやっていることです
I don't design electronics
私は電子機器の設計はしません
I'm not going to take these either
これらも受け取るつもりはありません
Neither do I
私もそうではないです
Actually I also
実は私も
maybe we will
たぶんそうするでしょう
But we're not doing animal testing right now
しかし、私たちは現在動物実験を行っていません
neither do we
私たちもそうしません
we also ask the doctor
私たちも医者に聞きます
or who cooperates
または協力してくれる人
Let's learn about this together
これについて一緒に学びましょう
possibility
可能性
OK
OK
That
それか
for the rest of the time
残りの時間は
I
私
I still want
まだ欲しい
I think
私が思うに
still want to introduce
まだ紹介したい
what are we doing
私たちは何をしているのですか
because at least
なぜなら少なくとも
I just talked for so long
つい長々と話してしまったので
it's not what we do
それは私たちがやっていることではありません
Thanks
ありがとう
I just want to introduce
ただ紹介したいのは
what we do
私達がすること
I probably spent just a little bit of time left
たぶん残りわずかな時間を過ごしたんだろう
I just introduce an example
ほんの一例を紹介します
materials we use
私たちが使用する材料
It is also a conductive polymer material
導電性高分子材料でもあります
Its organic structure looks like this
有機的な構造はこんな感じ
If you want to know something today
今日何か知りたいことがあれば
I strongly recommend that you know we're doing big P
私たちが大きなPを行っていることを知っておくことを強くお勧めします
This material is called PEDOT for short.
この材料は略してPEDOTと呼ばれます。
no Chinese
中国人はいない
English is called PEDOT
英語ではPEDOTといいます。
When you talk about PEDOT, everyone knows it better.
PEDOT について話すと、誰もがよく知っています。
that this material
この素材が
What I'm introducing to you is
今回ご紹介するのは、
of organic electronics
有機エレクトロニクスの
how to say
どのように言って
if you are american
あなたがアメリカ人なら
You say the Michael Jackson of organic electronics
有機エレクトロニクス界のマイケル・ジャクソンって言うんですね
Or the Jay Chou of organic electronics
あるいは有機エレクトロニクス界のジェイ・チョウ
He's the Super Young of the Organic Electronics World
彼は有機エレクトロニクス界のスーパーヤングです
His patent expired last year
彼の特許は昨年切れた
Then the whole world is making this material
そして全世界がこの素材を作っている
parks in taiwan
台湾の公園
Wait for me to ask, I said how to make this material
聞いて待って、この材料の作り方を言いました
Because this material is a super material for organic electronics
この材料は有機エレクトロニクスのスーパー材料であるため
its cause
その原因
it has a chemical reason
それには化学的な理由がある
Let me analyze it a little bit with you because I think
私はこう思うので、あなたと一緒にそれを少し分析しましょう
It is my responsibility
それは私の責任です
You can see double bond single bond
二重結合、単結合が見えます
This is the basic one
これが基本的なものです
The structure of conductive polymer
導電高分子的結構
But a very important issue in conducting polymers is
しかし、導電性ポリマーにおける非常に重要な問題は、
these two positions
この2つの立場
would have been empty
空いていただろう
if you are empty in
あなたが空っぽなら
When making this film, there may be
この映画を作るときに、
Accidentally connect the wrong look
誤って間違った外観を接続してしまう
it is possible to get here
ここに着くことは可能です
If you have a handle, please draw it
ハンドルをお持ちの方は描いてください
If this key is accidentally attached here
このキーが誤ってここに接続された場合
It will not form a single bond double bond single bond double bond structure
単結合二重結合単結合二重結合構造を形成しません
Then its conductivity will become poor.
そうすると導電性が悪くなってしまいます。
the second is
2番目は
So in this molecule these two positions are completely blocked
したがって、この分子ではこれら 2 つの位置が完全にブロックされています
And the two oxygen
そして2つの酸素
will provide a function
機能を提供します
it will make this one thing
それはこれ一つのものを作ります
Oxidation Potential Decrease
酸化電位の低下
become more suitable for
より適したものになる
Use in normal condition
通常の状態で使用する
Do not use at too high a potential
あまり高い電位で使用しないでください
so
それで
This molecule has a very ingenious structure
この分子は非常に巧妙な構造をしています
it accomplishes many things
それは多くのことを達成します
it has high conductivity
高い導電性を持っています
it has few flaws
欠点がほとんどない
and very stable
そして非常に安定しています
because all its places are filled
どこも埋まってるから
impossible
不可能
There will be various
色々あるでしょう
And it's conductive this element
そして、この要素は導電性があります
blocked in this all
この全てにおいてブロックされている
middle of molecular structure
分子的結構中間
that first this
それは最初にこれ
Polymer is a
ポリマーというのは、
Bayer AG
バイエルAG
Developed by Bayer AG
バイエル社が開発
So at first it had a
最初は
The commercial name is called Biochrome
商品名はバイオクロームといいます
but then
しかしその後
Everyone knows Peter
誰もがピーターを知っています
then later became Helix Corporation
その後ヘリックス株式会社となる
so it's so far
それでそれは遠いです
it's in all sorts of places you
それはあらゆる種類の場所にあります
In fact, conductive polymers, we all think that they
実際、導電性ポリマーは誰もがそう思っています。
This electronic component
この電子部品は
OLED, none of us has OLED, not everyone has an LED TV
OLED、私たちの誰も OLED を持っていません、誰もが LED TV を持っているわけではありません
But some conductive polymers
ただし、一部の導電性ポリマー
Already used in your daily life
すでに日常生活で使われている
like solid capacitors
固体コンデンサのような
Solid capacitors are basically poly pyro
固体コンデンサは基本的にポリパイロです
They are all skin-determined solid capacitors
これらはすべて表皮で決定される固体コンデンサです
Because his capacitance is also very good
静電容量も非常に優れているので、
even solid capacitors, even supercapacitors
固体コンデンサ、スーパーコンデンサさえも
conductive polymer
導電性ポリマー
So this material already has very, very many possibilities
つまり、この素材にはすでに非常に多くの可能性が秘められています
It contains organic thermoelectric materials
有機熱電材料が含まれています
Organic Antistatic Materials
有機帯電防止材料
Contains ultracapacitor material
ウルトラキャパシター素材を含む
Even contains organic color-changing glass
有機色変化ガラスも含まれています
Many people are doing this thermoelectric material
多くの人がこの熱電材料を開発しています
So I say this material is the Jay Chou of the organic electronics world
したがって、この素材は有機エレクトロニクス界のジェイ・チョウであると言えます。
Just remember, it is Jay Chou
覚えておいてください、ジェイ・チョウです
When I see Jay Chou, I think of him
ジェイ・チョウを見ると彼のことを思い出します
OK, let's continue to introduce
さて、紹介を続けていきましょう
Our own laboratory, in fact, one of the characteristics of the organic
実は、私たち自身の研究所も、オーガニックの特徴の一つです。
because you have all kinds of organic structures
あらゆる種類の有機構造があるからです
So we can use organic synthesis
有機合成が使えるようになります
To bring out the functionality of the material we want
素材の求める機能を引き出すために
brought out in molecular design, we can control its molecular design
分子設計で導き出され、分子設計を制御できる
In nanostructures, we can use such materials
ナノ構造では、このような材料を使用できます
Can form different nanostructures
さまざまなナノ構造を形成可能
Of course because today we're going to talk about nanostructures
もちろん、今日はナノ構造について話すからです
So I won't introduce you to nanostructures anymore
したがって、ナノ構造についてはもう紹介しません。
We can take advantage of its nanostructure
そのナノ構造を活用できる
It's like saying we have two weapons
武器が2つあると言っているようなものだ
That is, if we put it together
つまり、まとめると
We can be applied in many, many aspects of biomedicine
私たちは生物医学の多くの側面に応用できます
The pope that contains biological images is going to be done in our laboratory
生物学的画像を含む教皇は私たちの研究室で行われる予定です
Contains biological detection
生物学的検出が含まれています
Often a speech might be either this or this
多くの場合、スピーチはこれまたはこれのいずれかになります
It is biological detection
生物学的検出です
or organic bioelectronics
または有機バイオエレクトロニクス
Then I will just introduce to you today
それでは今日はちょっとだけご紹介します
we are in our laboratory
私たちは研究室にいます
By different molecular design
異なる分子設計による
we can list
リストできます
We can design two kinds of molecules
2種類の分子を設計できる
One is able to bring out its importance
その重要性を引き出すことができる
For example, there are some organic shut-off groups at the end
たとえば、最後には有機的な遮断グループがいくつかあります。
Or you could say it's a living organism's shutdown mechanism
あるいは、それは生物の活動停止メカニズムであると言えるかもしれません。
Because it contains succinic acid and contains amine groups
コハク酸を含み、アミン基を含むため
Even contains some like this Malayimid
このようなマレーミド語も含まれています
or some sugar group
またはいくつかの糖グループ
Even or some groups of stacked eggs
積み重ねられた卵の偶数またはいくつかのグループ
It can quickly combine with living organisms as a co-pilot
副操縦士として生体と素早く合体することができる
And produce the functionalities we need
必要な機能を生成します
on the other hand
一方で
It has another set of monomers
別のモノマーセットがあります
is used to control the properties of the surface of the material
材料の表面の特性を制御するために使用されます
For example, we can touch the surface
たとえば、表面に触れることができます。
Pick up a lot of Foki
フォキをたくさん拾う
Then connect with Doverki and he becomes
次に、Doverki と接続すると、彼は次のようになります。
Teflon like material
テフロンのような素材
Can
できる
Nonstick
ノンスティック
can do many things
たくさんのことができる
can also be connected
接続することもできます
For example, water-based materials
たとえば、水系の材料
especially these
特にこれら
very very clear material
とてもとても透明な素材
Include
含む
Polyethylene glycol
ポリエチレングリコール
contains some
いくつか含まれています
Dielectric materials
誘電体材料
can let him
彼に任せることができます
can go
行くことができる
lead him to the organism's
彼を生物のところに連れて行きます
Binding is very, very selective
バインディングは非常に選択的です
These are actually
これらは実際には
we are imitating
私たちは真似をしています
Molecular Design in Organisms
生物の分子設計
we just put
私たちはただ置いただけです
put it on the main chain
メインチェーンに付けます
replace us
私たちを置き換えてください
Just the conductive polymer material you want to use
使いたい導電性高分子材料だけを
The most important thing is that we first have
最も重要なことは、最初に
More than 80 such monomers
80以上のそのようなモノマー
has been synthesized
合成されました
probably also
おそらくまた
Because in fact, it is probably one of the labs that have done the most
おそらく最も多くの成果を上げているラボの 1 つであるため、
On the other hand, they can also be processed by a different so-called molding process
一方、別のいわゆる成形プロセスで加工することもできます。
Or the process of real science, the process of Lysography
あるいは、本物の科学のプロセス、リソグラフィーのプロセス
They can make all kinds of different, different difficult materials
彼らはあらゆる種類の異なる、異なる困難な材料を作ることができます
I just want to introduce to you, we have done some
紹介したいのですが、私たちはいくつかのことを行いました
All kinds of materials with thin films and materials with rice noodles
各種薄膜素材、ビーフン素材
Material with resistant rice grains
米粒がつきにくい素材
There are also hollow resistant rice grain materials
中空になりにくい米粒材もございます
There are even some like fibers, fibrous materials
繊維のようなものもあります。
Even the material of the rice point, even the material of the rice column
稲点の素材も 稲柱の素材も
We've all done a lot, a lot of different materials
私たちは皆、たくさんの、たくさんの異なる素材を作りました
Why?
なぜ？
right?
右？
So in a situation like this
それで、このような状況では
We make such a wide variety of materials
こんなに多種多様な素材を作っているのですね
Can be applied in different places
さまざまな場所に適用できます
can control
コントロールできる
In the experiment we started with
から始めた実験では
we want to control cells
細胞をコントロールしたい
i.e. living organisms
つまり生物
because it is called an organism
それは生物と呼ばれるものだから
It is unlikely that we will directly make chairs
椅子を直接作ることは考えられません
Let's start with cells
細胞から始めましょう
Do a cell experiment in vitro
インビトロで細胞実験を行う
We can understand cells in living organisms
生物の細胞を理解できる
How can the best behave
最高の人はどのように行動できるか
ok , now back to the one thing i just said
さて、先ほど言ったことに戻ります
As I said, when I first started PHS
先ほども言いましたが、PHSを始めたばかりの頃は
I really want to directly
本当は直接言いたいのですが
buy one
一つ買う
Actually I said
実は私が言いました
It seems that we have asked our professor
教授に聞いたみたいです
Can I buy a piece of TFT
TFTを購入できますか
then cut it all
それから全部切ります
Then stuff it in that animal
それからそれをその動物に詰め込みます
That
それか
Let's see if we can record the animal's telegram.
動物の電報を録音できるかどうか見てみましょう。
that's
それは
Actually this should not work
実際にはこれは機能しないはずです
Why
なぜ
I will introduce you a little
少し紹介させていただきます
This thing is called obligatory response
こういうのを義務的対応というんだよ
i believe in speaking obligatory response
私は話すことが義務的な応答であると信じています
You may feel
と感じるかもしれません
clam what is this
ハマグリ、これは何ですか
But everyone has probably been hurt
でもきっと誰もが傷ついたことがあるはず
everyone will notice that
誰もがそれに気づくだろう
If you accidentally drop something
うっかり物を落としてしまったら
into your hand
あなたの手に
how will your hands react
あなたの手はどう反応しますか
it doesn't bleed all the time
いつも血が出るわけではない
it won't bleed
血は出ません
it will find a way to heal it
それを治す方法を見つけてくれるだろう
The way it goes to treat it is simple
治療方法は簡単です
it's in your
それはあなたの中にあります
It only has this obligation to go in
入る義務があるだけです
It triggers a series of immune responses
一連の免疫反応を引き起こします
Let your body automatically produce a protective function
身体が自動的に防御機能を発揮できるようにする
This protective function means
この保護機能とは、
wrap it up
急いでください
create a thin membrane to wrap it around
薄い膜を作って包み込む
wrap that thick film around it
その厚いフィルムを巻き付けます
that so
まあまあ
You may have heard many such testimonies
あなたもそのような証言をたくさん聞いたことがあるかもしれません
that is to say, for example
つまり、たとえば
during world war two
第二次世界大戦中
There are a lot of people who take out some kind of shards of glass in their heads
頭の中にガラスの破片のようなものを取り出す人がたくさんいます
They are comparable to this shard of glass
それらはこのガラスの破片に匹敵します
Or a bunch of these eggshells were taken out all over the body.
あるいは、この卵の殻が体中から大量に取り出された。
Somebody even has a bullet and stays in that
誰かがそこにとどまるための弾丸さえ手に入れた
Of course some are comics and some are real
もちろん漫画もあれば本物もある
In fact, sometimes comics are written like real
実際、漫画は本物のように書かれることもあります
I don't know which is real and which is manga
どれが本物でどれが漫画なのか分からない
But many such cases exist
しかし、そのようなケースは数多く存在します
That's actually the body's natural protective response.
それは実際には体の自然な防御反応です。
when he sees something
彼が何かを見るとき
He thinks it's not time for amypods
彼はアミポッドの時期ではないと考えている
He is learning the Great Wall right next to him
彼はすぐ隣で万里の長城を学んでいます
separate it
分けて
It's not just this but all objects will have a reaction
これに限らずあらゆる物体が反応します
so but just thinking about it
だから、でも考えただけでも
Then you go in with such a thin chip
それからあなたはそのような薄いチップで入ります
For him, detail is something he has never seen in his body
彼にとって、細部は自分の体の中で見たことのないものです
There is actually no thin body in that body
その体には実際には薄い体はありません
what should he do
彼は何をすべきか
Of course he treats it as a foreign object
もちろん異物扱い
So the thin wafer goes in
薄いウェーハが入ります
He's sure to make a thick layer of it
彼はきっとそれを厚くしてくれるだろう
And then you want to see your thick biological layer
そしてあなたは自分の厚い生体層を見たいと思うでしょう
is an insulating layer
絶縁層です
It must prevent the signal from being transmitted
信号の送信を防止する必要があります
So in this case
したがって、この場合には
There is no way we can continue to use this chip
このチップを使い続けることはできません
so for this matter
それでこの件に関しては
what we can do is
私たちにできることは
We can do proper molecular design
適切な分子設計が可能
Find a way to turn this immune response
この免疫反応を変える方法を見つける
or protection
または保護
suppress it
それを抑制する
That is a very common method
それは非常に一般的な方法です
is the so-called use
いわゆる使い方です
Bionic materials
バイオニック材料
we are hospitalized at central
私たちは中央病院に入院しています
when i was in japan
日本にいたとき
have also developed a series of
のシリーズも開発しました
Organic Conductive Materials Imitating Cell Membranes
細胞膜を模倣した有機導電性材料
That is to say
つまり
look carefully
よく見て
Today the cell membrane is made of a pile of paper
現在、細胞膜は紙の山でできています
form the cell membrane
細胞膜を形成する
it is clear water on one side
片側は澄んだ水です
one side is water
片面は水です
Today if we put the water delivery end
今日で水の配達を終了したら
All replaced with conductive polymer
全て導電性ポリマーに置き換え
Then keep the water list
それから水リストを保管してください
In this way we get a material
このようにしてマテリアルを入手します
Much like a cell membrane, but it retains its clear water end
細胞膜によく似ていますが、透明な水の端を保持しています。
At the same time, on this conductive polymer, we can also learn how cells
同時に、この導電性ポリマーでは、細胞がどのように機能するかを学ぶこともできます。
to lead to some specific identification
何らかの特定の識別につながる
For example, there are various proteins on the cell membrane
例えば、細胞膜にはさまざまなタンパク質が存在します。
Cell recognition using amino acids and even sugars
アミノ酸や糖も使った細胞認識
We can all use molecular design to induce such cell recognition
私たちは皆、分子設計を使用してこのような細胞認識を誘導することができます
For example, we can connect various protein leagants to conductive polymers
たとえば、さまざまなタンパク質レガントを導電性ポリマーに接続できます。
Some of the so-called ligands of these proteins are currently commonly used in academia
これらのタンパク質のいわゆるリガンドのいくつかは、現在学界で一般的に使用されています。
So ours contains the so-called RGD, a leapt like RGD
したがって、私たちのものにはいわゆるRGD、RGDのようなリープトが含まれています
Or the leanant like IKVAV, the leanant of RGD is cut out from the so-called collagen
またはIKVAVのようなリーナント、RGDのリーナントはいわゆるコラーゲンから切り出されます
We can control this interface
このインターフェースを制御できます
can achieve what we want to do is
私たちがやりたいことを達成できるのは、
At the same time, it will not produce rejection reaction with organisms
同時に、生物に対して拒絶反応を引き起こしません。
What about such a design?
こんなデザインはどうでしょうか？
We did some simple experiments
いくつかの簡単な実験をしました
Although simple
シンプルですが
But the whole experiment took about three or four years
しかし、実験全体には約3、4年かかりました
from molecular design
分子設計から
From designing one like this one
このようなデザインから
one that can culture cells
細胞を培養できるもの
simple one
単純なもの
one
一個
a so-called platform
いわゆるプラットフォーム
Then we grow cells on top of
次に、その上で細胞を成長させます。
Coated with our different materials
当社の異なる材料でコーティング
let's compare it
比べてみましょう
appearance of cultured cells
培養細胞の様子
so
それで
I can only give you a brief report on the results
結果については簡単な報告しかできません
These two are compared
この二つを比較すると
This is the control group
これはコントロールグループです
These two are the experimental group
この二人は実験グループです
One of the experimental group had applied voltage
実験グループの 1 人は電圧を印加しました
one without voltage
電圧のないもの
We use our new biomimetic cell membrane conductive polymer
新しい生体模倣細胞膜導電性ポリマーを使用しています
And in the case of appropriate private family pressure
そして、家族からの適切な個人的な圧力の場合には、
We achieved a very good result of stimulating the growth of nerve cells
神経細胞の成長を促進するという非常に良い結果が得られました。
That is to say, we use the simplest way
つまり、最も単純な方法を使用します
is the way we look at how fast neuron protrusions can grow
ニューロンの突起がどのくらいの速さで成長するかを調べる方法です
let's measure
測ってみましょう
What we get is one of the highest values ​​ever seen on the striae
私たちが得たものは、脈理でこれまでに観察された中で最も高い値の 1 つです
about two and a half times higher
約2.5倍高い
That is, there is an increase in length of 1.5 times
つまり、長さは1.5倍になります。
It's just a simple application of a voltage and some molecular design
電圧と分子設計を単純に適用するだけです
I think the most important reason is because we are in such a biomimetic molecular interface
最も重要な理由は、私たちがそのような生体模倣分子界面にいるからだと思います。
We make sure that the electron follows this
電子がこれに従うことを確認します
There is a good electron ion transfer effect between cells
セル間の電子イオン移動効果が良好です。
That is to say, such an electrical signal can properly enter the ions through
つまり、このような電気信号は、
ions are generated inside
内部でイオンが発生
As for the very detailed
非常に詳しいことに関しては
Very detailed Mechanism
非常詳細的Mechanism
In fact, we have until now
実際、私たちはこれまでに
We are still looking for
まだ募集中です
How to do such an experiment
このような実験はどのように行うか
But in the early days of this
しかし、この初期の頃は、
in the design of a so-called platform
いわゆるプラットフォームの設計において
We've seen very, very good results
非常に良い結果が得られました
Of course this thing is just us
もちろん、これは私たちだけのことです
small step
小さな一歩
We also did a series of
シリーズもやりました
New things
新的東西
include us
私たちも含めて
So this thing is in
それで、これは入っています
most importantly
最も重要なこと
we are at
私たちは〜にて
We can use this cell membrane
この細胞膜を利用できるのです
for electrical stimulation
電気刺激用
Application of so-called electrostimulatory cell engineering
いわゆる電気刺激細胞工学の応用
We hope that in the future we can use it to make
将来的にはそれを活用して、
The so-called electrical spine
いわゆる電気脊椎
Neuroelectric spines can stimulate nerve growth
神経電気スパインは神経の成長を刺激することができます
Today if there is an unfortunate patient who has the so-called
今日、いわゆる不幸な患者がいるとしたら、
The so-called spinal injury
いわゆる脊髄損傷
or when there is an acute need
または緊急の必要がある場合
we need to be able to help them
私たちは彼らを助けることができる必要があります
Can stimulate the growth of electric cells
電気細胞の成長を刺激することができます
But it's still early
でもまだ早いよ
Just reached the cell level
細胞レベルに達したばかり
Cell Hierarchy
セル階層
not only
だけでなく
I give this example
この例を挙げます
In fact, let everyone know
実はみんなに知らせて
Such a simple and deceptively simple result
とても単純で一見単純な結果
Contains three parts
3つの部分が含まれています
Contains our molecular design above
上記の分子設計が含まれています
Include you want to design a
デザインしたいことを含めてください
so-called components
いわゆるコンポーネント
This is of course not an electronic component
これは確かに電子部品ではありません
But the simplest element
しかし、最も単純な要素は、
We have two electrodes here
ここには 2 つの電極があります
Between the two electrodes there is a
2 つの電極の間には、
there is a get
ゲットがある
this get
これを入手
cause we can add 4 plus voltage
4プラス電圧を追加できるからです
On a simple cell like this
このような単純なセルでは
So we have a simple electrode design
したがって、単純な電極設計ができました
But you have to have elements like this
しかし、このような要素が必要です
It stimulates the growth of cells
細胞の成長を刺激します
Which means you need to have a variety of people
つまり、多様な人が必要だということです
And then finally you have to be able to analyze the results of the cells
そして最後に、セルの結果を分析できるようにする必要があります。
That
それか
I just had a little time to introduce a
少し時間があったので紹介しましたが、
different
違う
An idea that I researched, I would like to share with you
私が調べたアイデアを皆さんと共有したいと思います
That is to say, our other piece
つまり、私たちのもう一つの作品
what we are doing is called
私たちがやっていることは呼ばれています
so-called smart material
いわゆるスマートマテリアル
Of course every time I talk about wisdom material
もちろん知恵ネタについて話すたびに
will want
欲しいでしょう
In particular, we will put our own laboratory
特に、私たちは独自の研究室を置きます
Organic Smart Materials Laboratory
有機スマート材料研究室
of course there is always someone
もちろんいつも誰かがいる
Especially some students may come to me and say
特に学生の中には私のところに来てこう言う人もいるかもしれません。
Teacher, I'm not smart enough, can I come in?
先生、私はあまり賢くないので入ってもいいですか？
then i can only say
それなら私はただ言うことができます
he
他
right
右
he is smart
彼は賢いです
us
私たち
As long as everyone works hard
みんなが頑張れば
don't need to be smart
賢くなる必要はない
We are all about designing smart materials
私たちはスマートなマテリアルをデザインすることに全力を注いでいます
to help our underserved humans
十分なサービスを受けられていない人類を助けるために
So what we call smart material
私たちがスマートマテリアルと呼ぶもの
let me introduce you a little bit
少し紹介させてください
smart material that is
スマートな素材です
you
あなた
In fact, the human body
実は人間の体は、
In the human body we have a variety of materials
人間の体の中にはさまざまな物質が存在しています
The material of the human body is actually a smart material
人体の素材は実はスマート素材
for example very simple
たとえば非常に単純な
when you are attacked by an
何かに襲われたとき
will naturally fight back
自然に反撃するだろう
when you get a stimulus
刺激を受けたとき
your body will go naturally
あなたの体は自然に動きます
elicit a series of subsequent responses
その後の一連の反応を引き出す
cause the body to be protected
体が守られるようにする
no harm, right?
害はありませんね？
the human body is simple
人間の体は単純です
If you come alone with your fist
拳を持って一人で来たら
you will hide
あなたは隠れるでしょう
you can't hide
隠すことはできません
Because this is a natural intelligent response of the human body
これは人体の自然な知的反応であるため、
So the so-called wisdom will be the same
だからいわゆる知恵も同じだろう
That is to say, when we are stimulated by an external
つまり、外部からの刺激を受けると、
it will generate form
フォームを生成します
or various changes
またはさまざまな変更
so it can respond to
に対応できるように
It can produce a different state
異なる状態を生み出すことができる
The stimuli generated by this include a variety of
それによって生じる刺激は多種多様です
There are so-called physical stimuli
いわゆる物理的刺激がある
Contains temperature light
温度光を含む
even magnetic fields, electric fields
磁場、電場さ​​えも
chemical stimulation
化学刺激
Contains pH
pHを含む
Contains electrochemical reactions
電気化学反応が含まれています
Contains even your tolerance to change it
それを変えるタブーさえも含まれています
change it this organic this
それをこのオーガニックに変えてください
change it to this
これに変更します
change its volume or receptor
ボリュームまたは受容体を変更する
Biological words contain the simplest is
生物学的な単語には、最も単純なものが含まれます。
If your blood sugar is too high today
今日の血糖値が高すぎる場合
you naturally secrete insulin
自然にインスリンが分泌される
This contains what is called a sugar stimulus
これにはいわゆる糖刺激が含まれています
Contains even an enzyme stimulating
刺激酵素も配合
Of course it also contains some
もちろん中にも含まれています
Simple stimulation of a receptor and carrier
受容体とキャリアの単純な刺激
it's all possible
それはすべて可能です
Then we do a very simple experiment
次に、非常に簡単な実験を行います
We designed another molecule
私たちは別の分子を設計しました
You don't have to worry about what the molecule looks like
分子がどのように見えるかを心配する必要はありません
You just need to know what the molecule can do
必要なのはその分子が何ができるかを知ることだけです
After this molecule is oxidized
分子が酸化された後
can make a cell or a protein
細胞やタンパク質を作ることができる
Connected to this oxidized shutdown group
この酸化されたシャットダウングループに接続されています
Then whenever restore
その後、復元するたびに
The cell or the functional group will leave
細胞または官能基が離れる
So we did a very simple experiment
そこで私たちは非常に簡単な実験を行いました
This is two sets of electrodes
これらは 2 セットの電極です
If we only oxidize
酸化するだけなら
For electrode 1, only electrode 1 will be connected to something
電極 1 の場合、電極 1 のみが何かに接続されます
Here we are very simple, we use a green dye
ここでは非常にシンプルで、緑色の染料を使用します。
So we only oxidize electrode 1, there will be green on the electrode
したがって、電極 1 のみを酸化すると、電極上には緑色が表示されます。
If we oxidize electrode 1 and electrode 2, there will be green on both electrode 1 and electrode 2
電極 1 と電極 2 を酸化すると、電極 1 と電極 2 の両方に緑色が現れます。
If we only restore electrode 2 at this time, only the green on electrode 2 will run away
このとき電極 2 だけを復元すると、電極 2 の緑色だけが逃げてしまいます。
That is, this is one, I just mentioned to you
つまり、これが 1 つです。先ほどお話しました。
An organism is a dynamic system
生物は動的なシステムです
In other words, we now also have a dynamic system to match the dynamic system of organisms
言い換えれば、私たちは生物の動的システムに適合する動的システムも手に入れたということです。
We hope this will help the organism to do something
これが生物が何かをするのに役立つことを願っています
We do simple things that are actually very intuitive
私たちは実際には非常に直感的な単純なことを行っています
Let's just say that after we increase the cells through the TV
テレビを通して細胞を増やしてから言ってみましょう
Everyone, I have done cell experiments
皆さん、細胞実験をしてきました
In fact, you may also know that there is a problem with the cells, the cells are very, very
実際、細胞に問題があることもご存知かもしれません。細胞は非常に状態が悪いのです。
Some cells are very sticky
一部の細胞は非常に粘着性が高い
like sticking to a surface
表面に張り付くような
Then you want to remove the cells from this surface
次に、この表面から細胞を削除したいとします。
For example, today I
たとえば、今日私は、
Say it like this
このように言ってください
I want to transplant this cell
この細胞を移植したい
from a thing
ある物から
port to something else
何か他のものに移植する
like today
今日のような
your
あなたの
Now there are many so-called stem cell therapeutics
現在、いわゆる幹細胞治療薬がたくさんあります。
therapy
治療法
that is
あれは
I use your stem cells
あなたの幹細胞を使用します
After protruding a layer of cornea
角膜層が突出した後
the cornea
角膜
must
必須
After being raised outside the body
体外で育てた後
must be transplanted back
元に移植しなければならない
on your eyes
あなたの目に
your eyes are useful
あなたの目は役に立ちます
but
しかし
Many times on the surface of in vitro cultures
体外培養物の表面で何度も
it's very, very sticky
とてもとても粘着性があります
if we don't do some
何かをしなければ
so-called smart materials
いわゆるスマートマテリアル
In that case, we can only scrape it with all our strength.
こうなったら全力で削るしかない。
Then when you scrape it with all your strength
そして力いっぱいこすってみると
cells will be lost
細胞が失われます
it won't come out nicely from the surface
表面からはうまく出ません
Does this mean that everyone has been injured?
ということは全員が怪我をしたということでしょうか？
If it's actually a bad habit of mine
それが本当に私の悪い癖なら
When you get hurt, when you see a scar, you want to pick it
傷つくと傷を見ると摘みたくなる
It will bleed again after picking
摘むとまた血が出る
this is such a concept
これはそのような概念です
Today if the cells have grown
今日、細胞が成長したら
I use Mechanical 4 to use mechanical power
機械動力を使用するにはメカニカル 4 を使用します
when to dig it up
いつ掘り出すか
its cells get hurt
その細胞は傷つきます
then it won't work well
それではうまくいきません
If we use a fun
楽しいものを使うなら
we use a
私たちはを使用します
Let's say we use heat-reactive stuff
熱反応性のものを使用するとします
We just take an ice cube and put it on
氷を取り出してそれを置くだけです
Now there are many new generation tapes that are heat reactive
現在、熱反応性を備えた新世代のテープが多数あります。
For example, if you blow it with a hair dryer
例えばドライヤーで乾かすと
it has no glue residue
接着剤の残留物はありません
That is, in cases like this
つまり、このような場合には、
We can achieve the situation of no residual glue
糊残りゼロを実現します
so i want to tell you
だから私はあなたに言いたいです
We also use this situation
私たちもこの状況を利用します
We are at this time under the method of telephone learning
現在、電話学習という方法をとっております。
We can make this layer of cells can leave the surface
この細胞層を表面から離れることができるようにすることができます
We can detect this cell
この細胞を検出できます
still alive very very well
まだとても元気に生きています
OK, this last two
OK、最後の 2 つは
Two is one of our simple
2 つは私たちのシンプルな方法の 1 つです
Share it with everyone
みんなと共有しましょう
Experimental results in our own laboratory
自社研究室での実験結果
Of course such an experiment
もちろんそんな実験も
away from real commercial applications
実際の商用アプリケーションから離れて
Or the application of future technology?
それとも未来のテクノロジーの応用でしょうか？
still have a very long distance
まだとても長い距離があります
but we believe
でも私たちは信じています
The whole thread of science should be
科学の全体の流れはこうあるべきです
we should be
我々はする必要があります
Study science with curiosity
好奇心を持って科学を学ぶ
what about science
科学はどうですか
New Science
新的Science
Will lead to new technology
新しい技術につながる
new technology
新技術
will lead new industries
新しい産業をリードするでしょう
The new industry will generate a new economy
新しい産業が新しい経済を生み出す
Then such words
するとそんな言葉が
This is the correct context
これが正しいコンテキストです
and we don't need to say
そして言う必要はありません
I have to take care of myself
自分のことは自分でしなければいけない
We actually focus on the front end
実際にはフロントエンドに重点を置いています
We want to do the best science
私たちは最高の科学を実現したいと考えています
hope this will
そうなるように願っています
can help everyone
みんなを助けることができる
then i last
それから私は最後です
make a brief summary
簡単な要約をする
uh, this is not actually a summary
ああ、これは実際には要約ではありません
I conclude that I put a picture just to tell everyone that this is something that our laboratory is doing
最後に、これが私たちの研究室が行っていることであることを皆さんに伝えるために写真を載せました。
Actually quite a lot
実はかなり多い
Then I hope that today's speech can make everyone understand the organic bioelectronic components
それでは、今日の講演で皆さんに有機バイオエレクトロニクスコンポーネントについて理解していただければ幸いです
I think it's a new field
新しい分野だと思います
But why do I think it's new?
しかし、なぜそれが新しいと思うのでしょうか？
Because sometimes I feel lonely
時々孤独を感じるから
because we did it for 10 years
10年もやってるから
It seems that there are still not many people doing it
まだまだやっている人は少ないようです
So we think maybe when we sometimes wonder if it's
だから私たちは、時々「もしかしたら」と思うとき、「もしかしたら」と考えるのです。
because it's worthless
それは無価値だから
But I think we most want to do this 10 years
でも、私たちが一番やりたいのはこれを10年だと思う
We think this is a very interesting field
これは非常に興味深い分野だと思います
And he and we are on this land
そして彼と私たちはこの土地にいる
I think there is a fate that is closely related
密接に関係する運命があると思います
Because I think he has a very close connection with our current electronics industry
なぜなら、彼は現在のエレクトロニクス産業と非常に密接な関係があると思うからです。
if there is a chance
機会があれば
This is the ability to continue to the technical level
これは技術レベルまで継続できる能力です
Even to the industrial level
産業レベルまで
that is our own hope
それは私たち自身の希望です
Then our specialty is material design including molecular design
そして、私たちの専門は分子設計を含めた材料設計です。
Hope to end up with some new apps
いくつかの新しいアプリが完成することを願っています
and new ways to help people
そして人々を助ける新しい方法
whether in biomedicine
生物医学であろうと
Sometimes we also do some research on energy
時にはエネルギーに関する研究も行います
Hope this can help you too
これがあなたにも役立つことを願っています
That's it, thank you all
以上です、皆さんありがとうございました
right now we
今、私たちは
Thank you Dr. You for your wonderful speech
博士、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとう
So we probably still have
だから、おそらくまだ残っているでしょう
i think almost 40 minutes
40分近くだと思います
you can ask some questions
いくつか質問することができます
there is one here
ここに一つあります
ask the professor
教授に聞く
The neurostimulation electric shock that the professor just mentioned
先ほど先生がおっしゃった神経刺激電気ショックです。
later can
後でできます
treat that
それを治す
Are you doing martial arts?
格闘技やってるの？
How long do you have to wait?
どれくらい待たなければなりませんか？
because my newcomer has many
私の新人はたくさん持っているので
have this symptom
この症状がある
Um
えーっと
The question is
質問は
As for the problem of bone nerves, this is actually
骨神経の問題ですが、これは実は
What we are doing now is actually very advanced
私たちが今やっていることは、実は非常に先進的なものです
That is, we are still making cells, we have not yet made relics
つまり、私たちはまだ細胞を作っている段階であり、遺物はまだ作っていないのです。
I haven't done the straight road yet, but what you said is the so-called bone nerve stimulation
まだ一本道はやってないけど、君が言ったのはいわゆる骨神経刺激だよ
In fact, some people have already started to use bioelectrodes to do this.
実際、一部の人々はすでにこれを行うために生体電極を使用し始めています。
actually
実際
me, everyone can go
私、みんな行っていいよ
maybe try to
試してみるかも知れません
What I just said, the so-called things like RoboCop
今言った、いわゆるロボコップのようなもの
It's not impossible anymore
もう不可能ではない
in America , in Australia
アメリカで、オーストラリアで
There are already a lot of people who are already doing something like this
すでにこのようなことをやっている人はたくさんいます
included in the usa
米国に含まれる
There are some, you can find some so-called videos on YouTube
いわゆるビデオがいくつかあります。YouTube で見つけることができます。
Is someone already, for example, after he installed the legacy
たとえば、レガシーをインストールした後、すでに誰かがいるか
He can come out with electrodes, he uses the signals from his brain
彼は電極を使って外に出ることができ、脳からの信号を使用します
Directly control the walking of this foot
この足の歩行を直接制御します
He doesn't need to go through a mechanical principle
機械的な原理を通過する必要はありません
just don't need crutches
ただ松葉杖は必要ない
Instead, directly use your brain waves to control
代わりに、脳波を直接使用して制御します。
Control the walking of this foot
この足の歩行を制御します
on the other hand
一方で
It has nothing to do with the comparison of the five nerves.
五つの神経の比較とは何の関係もありません。
In Australia
オーストラリアで
They do what's called an inner ear transplant
彼らは内耳移植と呼ばれるものを行います
They use inner ear transplants
彼らは内耳移植を使用しています
Such neuroelectric ridges
電気脊椎
can stimulate
刺激できる
hearing recovery
聴力の回復
This experiment has been at least
この実験は少なくとも
What I saw last
最後に見たもの
At least 30,000 people have been transplanted like this
少なくとも3万人がこのように移植されている
A test of a so-called electrical spine for inner ear transplantation
内耳移植のいわゆる電気脊椎の検査
So these things are already being done
したがって、これらのことはすでに行われています
that just means
それはただの意味です
words on the hospital side
病院側の言葉
i have some nerves
少し神経質です
The surgeon has talked
外科医が話しました
that is
あれは
on the one hand
一方では
Does the patient need it?
患者はこれを必要としていますか
can we do it
できるでしょうか
Then the doctor can't do it
だったら医者は出来ないよ
This is
これは
we talk all the time
私たちはいつも話しています
Is it possible for something like this
このようなことは可能ですか
Of course, it is not limited to doing ancient nerves.
もちろん、古代の神経を行うことに限定されません。
and many other things
他にもたくさんのこと
How about that effect?
その効果はどうでしょうか？
I didn't do it when I was a kid
子供の頃はやってなかった
have not do yet
まだやっていない
because they haven't done it yet
彼らはまだそれをやっていないから
still too early
まだ早すぎる
because it's still a little early
まだ少し早いので
that's it
それでおしまい
Because we're not doctors after all
結局のところ私たちは医者ではないので、
So many times we don't
そうしないことが何度もある
we sometimes talk to the doctor
私たちは時々医者と話します
This is how cross-lingual cooperation looks like
言語を超えた協力はこんな感じ
we work with doctors
私たちは医師と協力しています
The doctor told us about the difficulties he faced
医師は私たちに彼が直面した困難について語った
Let's look at it from a scientist's point of view
科学者の視点から見てみましょう
From a technical point of view
技術的な観点から
what can we do with them
彼らに何ができるでしょうか
So I think for patients
だから私は患者さんのためにこう思います
I think the best channel of communication
最高のコミュニケーションチャネルだと思います
still a doctor
まだ医者です
because the doctor is a bridge
医者は架け橋だから
he can talk to us
彼は私たちと話すことができます
talk to patients
患者と話す
So the doctor will compare
したがって、この場合、医師は比較します
The doctor actually knows best, I think
実際には医者が一番よく知っていると思います
I still think the doctor knows best
やはり医者が一番よく知っていると思います
Thanks
ありがとう
ok here
はい、ここで
Teacher Yu, let me ask
ユウ先生、聞いてみましょう
You just mentioned that when the power is on
先ほど電源が入っているときについてお話しましたが、
Cells can be detached from surfaces
細胞は表面から剥がれる可能性がある
That's the surface of dealing with that culture name
それはその文化名を扱う表面的なものです
or processing cell membranes
または細胞膜の処理
surface of the name
名前の表面
The surface is just adding and coating or what?
表面はただ追加してコーティングしているだけですか？
Yes, such a surface is the surface of our electrode
はい、そのような表面が電極の表面です
Just add a coating of the conductive material we just made like this
このように先ほど作った導電性材料のコーティングを追加するだけです
So we can make it from the surface of this material
この材料の表面から作ることができます
make a proper disengagement
適切な離脱をする
So you just mentioned that corner ink may be a medical material or something.
それで、先ほどコーナーインクが医療材料か何かの可能性があるとおっしゃいました。
Jiaomo is another direction, but I know the direction
焦母は別の方向ですが、方向は知っています
However, when cells are cultured
しかし、一般的に細胞を培養すると、
It was necessary to take the cells out of the cultured cotton
培養綿から細胞を取り出す必要があった
to do splitting or something
分割か何かをするために
so this kind of look you cotton
だから、このような表情をしています、コットン
Should be pretty close to the application angle
適用角度にかなり近いはずです
That is to say, it can be used in general cultured cells
つまり、培養細胞全般に使用可能です。
That's right, it can be used for general cultured cells
そうです、培養細胞全般に使えます
But on the other hand, generally cultured cells
しかしその一方で、一般的な培養細胞は
Because what you said is right
あなたが言ったことは正しいから
That is to say, it can be used, but it depends on whether the cells need it
つまり、使用できますが、細胞がそれを必要とするかどうかによって異なります。
Some cells do not need
一部の細胞は必要ありません
Because traditional biochemical technology they, for example,
なぜなら、伝統的な生化学技術は、例えば、
by
に
Add the cell membrane protein degrading enzyme Tripsin
細胞膜タンパク質分解酵素トリプシンを添加
They use this to help it get off the surface
彼らはこれを表面から取り除くのに使用します
but in that case
しかしその場合は
It is said to be toxic to certain cells
特定の細胞に対して有毒だと言う
So really looking at the cells
実際に細胞を観察してみると、
if the cells need it
細胞がそれを必要とするなら
In fact, such technologies already exist.
実際、そのような技術はすでに存在しています。
I believe that there are experience or people in use
経験者や使っている人がいると思います
The most common one is actually not the electrical stimulation we are talking about now.
最も一般的なものは、実際には今話している電気刺激ではありません。
but thermal reactivity
しかし熱反応性
We are also doing thermal reactions
熱反応も行っています
there is a certain type of material
特定の種類の素材があります
It doesn't stick to cells when it's on ice
氷上では細胞にくっつかない
sticky cells when hot
熱いと粘着性のある細胞
This material is actually already sitting on the cornea
この物質は実際にはすでに角膜上に存在しています
Even sitting on the repair of cardiomyocytes
座って心筋細胞を修復する場合でも
research in this area
この分野の研究
It is already being done in Japan and Europe
日本やヨーロッパではすでに行われている
It uses this type of
このタイプを使用します
so-called smart material
いわゆるスマートマテリアル
But the heat response is exhausted and it is already being done
でも熱反応はもう限界でもう終わってる
Common cells are paired with few people who use this
一般的なセルは、これを使用する少数の人々とペアになっています
at least i haven't heard of it
少なくとも私は聞いたことがない
yes it can
はい、できます
Because I think maybe on the one hand
たぶん一方では思うから
Is there a need
必要はありますか
on the one hand
一方では
Then on the one hand is the price
それから一方では価格です
hello doc
こんにちは、ドクター
thank you for your excellent speech
素晴らしいスピーチをありがとう
I am Jianfu
私はジャンフです
I want to ask
聞きたいです
Just had an experiment with P.DOT
P.DOT で実験してみました
It has a potential
可能性を秘めています
With battery
有加電池機
One is pure P.DOT
1 つは純粋な P.DOT
There is another material
別の素材もあります
You mentioned that it's neurological growth
神経の成長だと言いましたね
Probably can be long now
おそらく今では長くなる可能性があります
About 2.5 times a speed
約2.5倍の速度
I want to ask
聞きたいです
P.DOT is in the process of applying voltage
P.DOTは電圧を印加中です
the directionality of its current
その電流の方向性
can be clearly located
明確に位置を特定できる
if its directionality
その方向性があれば
can be located
見つけることができます
that neuronal outgrowth
その神経細胞の成長
It is divided into S-Long and Dentrix
S-LongとDentrixに分かれる
the length of its growth
その成長の長さ
Is it possible to analyze the direction of his electrical stimulation?
彼の電気刺激の方向を分析することは可能ですか?
If there is a positive correlation between them in terms of angle
角度に関してそれらの間に正の相関がある場合
Maybe for the future judgment on potential and its directionality
将来の可能性とその方向性を判断するためかもしれません
And because we know that our creatures actually have a lot of traps on the surface
そして、私たちの生き物が実際に地表にたくさんの罠を仕掛けていることを私たちは知っているからです
It forms the potential area is a comprehensive effect of clustering
クラスタリングの総合効果で潜在領域を形成
But our biology actually tries to bring our body into balance
しかし、私たちの生物学は実際には私たちの体のバランスを保とうとします
So its mill actually has a microcirculation magnetic field in the
そのため、その工場には実際に微小循環磁場が存在します。
Maybe this material has a magnetic field for the microcirculation of the mill
おそらくこの材料には、工場の微小循環のための磁場があるのでしょう。
It can go to locate further things
さらに多くのものを探しに行くことができます
Will that affect the direction of our future nerve growth?
それは私たちの将来の神経成長の方向に影響を与えるのでしょうか？
and the direction of its stimulus
そしてその刺激的な方向性
Or even it pulses as often as it should
あるいは、必要なだけ頻繁に脈動することさえあります
The difference between the speed of change of its ions
そのイオンの変化速度の違い
Implementing the diff might help
diff を実装すると役立つかもしれません
This question is really too professional
この質問は本当に専門的すぎます
I say this question is very good
この質問はとても良いと思います
This is the question we all ask ourselves
これは私たち全員が自問する質問です
That is to say, this is actually one of our current research directions.
つまり、これが実は私たちの現在の研究の方向性の一つなのです。
but i want to be here
でも私はここにいたい
I always have to keep an open mind
常に心を開いておく必要がある
That is to say, there is a problem with what we are doing is that
つまり、私たちがやっていることには問題があるということです。
can we do
できるでしょうか
If you are interested we can always cooperate
ご興味がございましたら、いつでもご協力させていただきます
In fact, our biggest problem is to say
実際、私たちの最大の問題は次のとおりです。
We don't understand anything about the so-called electrophysiological
いわゆる電気生理学的現象については何も理解していません。
this part
この部分
That is to say, I will show you the result today.
ということで、今日はその結果をお見せします。
is an actually a very, very, very early result
これは実際には非常に、非常に、非常に初期の結果です
we just do one thing
私たちはただ一つのことをするだけです
let's go see
見に行きましょう
A chemist's point of view
化学者の視点
Watch us change the chemical structure
化学構造が変化する様子を観察してください
To simulate the structure of the cell membrane
細胞膜の構造をシミュレーションするには
How would it alter the growth of the cells
細胞の成長はどのように変化するのでしょうか
But the tiny part contains say
しかし、小さな部分には言うことが含まれています
power plant
発電所
electric current
電流
electric potential
電位
Even the micro current generated by the power plant
発電所で発生する微弱電流さえも
or the magnetic fields generated by power plants
または発電所によって生成される磁場
is there any way to change
変える方法はありますか
Go polar wise the growth of these cells
これらの細胞の成長を極地に進めます
Actually we really want to do
実は私たちが本当にやりたいのは、
But we are still working on
しかし、私たちはまだ取り組んでいます
how are we going to do this experiment
この実験はどうやってやるのですか
that is how we go
それが私たちのやり方です
How do we design this device
このデバイスをどのように設計するか
Let it produce the direction of a current we want
望む電流の方向を生成しましょう
In fact, even we are curious
実は私たち自身も興味津々です
because what i'm going to say is
なぜなら私が言おうとしているのは
I mean it from the bottom of my heart
心から言います
which means we're really, really curious
つまり、私たちは本当に、本当に興味があるということです
we've always wanted to do
私たちはいつもやりたかった
But it seems that there is still a lack of knowledge
でもまだ知識が少ないようです
Still looking for how to do this experiment
この実験の方法をまだ模索中
right
右
Thank you very much
どうもありがとうございます
I hope more people can benefit from this
より多くの人がこの恩恵を受けられることを願っています
we would love to do
私たちはぜひやりたいと思っています
because this also goes on to what's called cellular physiology
これはいわゆる細胞生理学にも関係するからです
or cell electronics
またはセルエレクトロニクス
Then we need or need more people
そうすると、もっと人が必要になる、あるいは必要になる
let us know tell us teach
教えてください教えてください
roughly how to do this kind of experiment
この種の実験を大まかに行う方法
We are now simply using
今は単純に使っています
The simplest way is to look at how a cell needs to be done from a chemical point of view.
最も簡単な方法は、化学的な観点からセルをどのように処理する必要があるかを検討することです。
Thanks
ありがとう
right
右
Does he have
彼は持っていますか
ok, there is
わかりました、あります
Yes, because it happens to be
はい、たまたまそうなったからです
I'm Dr. You's college classmate
私はドクター・ユーの大学の同級生です
He just said that all college students have joined TSMC
彼は大学生全員がTSMCに加わったと言いました
That Fengqiao is the only one present today
今日いるのは鳳橋だけだということ
I just happened to be the one who didn't get into TSMC
たまたまTSMCに参加できなかったのは私だけです
So when he said that just now, he still felt hot on his face.
だから今そう言った時も顔が熱かった。
as if talking about my feelings
自分の気持ちを語るかのように
like this
このような
Because that said there is still a major problem
とは言え、まだ大きな問題が残っているので、
Like the teacher’s first question just now, how can this thing be done?
先ほどの先生の最初の質問のように、これはどうすればできるのでしょうか。
because I've actually been posting the door for a while
私は実際にしばらくアナウンスのドアにいるので
Then we are probably more in the industry
そうすれば、私たちはおそらく業界にもっと参入するでしょう
As far as the most feared issue is to say
最も懸念されている問題に関して言えば、
you may do well in the lab
研究室ではうまくやれるかもしれない
when he started to enter Pirom
彼がピロムに入り始めたとき
The trader will tell you that he can't do it
トレーダーはあなたにそれはできないと言うでしょう
Or when this thing is made
あるいは、これが作られたとき
He's going to give it to a patient.
彼はそれを患者に与えるつもりだ。
The patient basically
基本的に患者さんは
Unless your thing is a very clear health insurance payment
よほど明確な健康保険の支払いでない限り
But we know we've heard that health insurance is about to break
しかし、私たちは医療が死につつあることを知っています
bankrupted
破産した
It's very likely
この可能性はかなり高いです
So the first question is to say
最初の質問はこう言います
this thing
このこと
probably first thing
おそらく最初のこと
because basically
なぜなら基本的に
What Dr. Post is doing in his lab now
ポスト博士は今研究室で何をしているのか
You have been doing it for ten years
10年もやってるのね
So the first of your industry's
つまり、業界初の
who this corporator might be
この法人は誰なのか
Under what circumstances are you prepared to count the turn
どのような状況でターンを数える準備ができていますか
And you start getting closer to maturity
そしてあなたは成熟に近づき始めます
You'll be thinking about mass production versus actual
大量生産と実際の生産について考えることになるでしょう
The question of the cost of being able to do this
これを実現するためのコストの問題
because I feel
感じているから
What Dr. Post just mentioned
ポスト博士が今述べたこと
Obviously not just in Science
明らかに科学だけではありません
or what Pay
または何を支払うか
Send a Paper on Science Network
Science Network に関する論文を送信する
the point is to say
ポイントは言うことです
When can he really form an industry
いつになったら本当に産業を形成できるのか
He can really use it in
彼は本当にそれを使えるのです
on people who need it
それを必要としている人たちに
So what you just said
それで、あなたが今言ったこと
doctor's part
医者の部分
I feel like jumping a little faster
もう少し早くジャンプしたい気分
The first thing to get lucky is
幸運を掴むためにまず最初にすべきことは、
Who can mass-produce this thing
誰がこんなものを量産できるだろうか
So your skill amount is
つまりあなたのスキル量は
who will do it first
誰が最初にやりますか
I think this is probably the most important
おそらくこれが最も重要だと思います
Because of this consideration
こういう配慮があるから
just a little less
ほんの少し少ない
How do you industrialize these
これをどうやって工業化するのですか
what is your idea
あなたの考えは
ok
Ok
this
これ
I think
私が思うに
classmate
同級生
no no no i just
いやいやいや、私はただ
just say hello
ただ挨拶してください
I think this part is actually
この部分は実際そうだと思う
In fact, my personal energy is actually quite complicated.
実際、私の個人的なエネルギーは非常に複雑です。
I think Zhou Fu just introduced some
周福がいくつか紹介したばかりだと思います
If I introduce myself, I actually
自己紹介をすると、実は
Like what they said about me returning home
彼らが言ったように、私は中国に戻りました
I feel like a wandering professor
放浪する教授のような気分だ
Because the highest record of this
最高記録なので
During my eight years with my wife
妻と過ごした8年間
changed four countries
4つの国を変えた
and moved seven times
そして7回引っ越した
sister will move
妹が引っ越します
Then I actually know how to set up the laboratory
それから私は実際に実験室をセットアップする方法を知っています
Because I often move labs
研究室を移動することが多いので
so off topic
とても話が逸れました
In fact, when I just graduated from PhD
実は私が博士課程を卒業したばかりの頃、
I have had conflicts
衝突もあったし
I have thought about what I want to do in the future
将来やりたいことを考えてみた
So actually I also have
それで、実は私も持っています
I have talked to VC
VCと話しました
I also talked to the industry
業界にも話を聞いた
I actually
私は実は
interviewed the industry
interview過業界
I also interviewed G Plastic
Gプラスチックにも取材してきました
I even interviewed McKenzie
マッケンジーにもインタビューした
McKenzie Consulting Firm
マッケンジー・コンサルティング会社
So actually I probably
だから実際私はおそらく
I probably understand what you're talking about
たぶん何のことを言っているのか理解できる
In fact, it's all very specialized.
実際、それはすべて非常に専門的です。
The point is you have to find
重要なのは、見つけなければならないということです
For me I think the key is you find the right person to help you
私にとって重要なのは、あなたを助けてくれる適切な人を見つけることだと思います
You need to find the right partner to help you
あなたを助けてくれる適切なパートナーを見つける必要があります
because no one person can do everything
一人の人がすべてをできるわけではないので、
I have no choice now
今は選択肢がありません
answer this question positively
この質問に肯定的に答える
I don't have a partner to help me now
今は助けてくれるパートナーがいない
The second is that I don't have any
2つ目は、何も持っていないということです
Our thing is actually for me
私たちのものは実は私のためのものです
I think the biggest problem is
最大の問題だと思うのは、
The first question just asked is very good
先ほどの最初の質問はとても良いです
which problem we can solve
私たちが解決できる問題はどれですか
Because what I'm offering now is a platform
なぜなら私が今提供しているのはプラットフォームだからです
Platforms have the potential to solve many problems
このプラットフォームは多くの問題を解決する可能性を秘めています
but to put it bluntly
しかし、率直に言って
you didn't solve any problems
あなたは何も問題を解決しませんでした
For example, the first question
たとえば、最初の質問は、
Another example, since organic bioelectronics is an emerging field
別の例として、有機バイオエレクトロニクスは新興分野であるため、
So I don't know, organic electronics in the organic electronics industry
だから分かりませんが、有機エレクトロニクスは有機エレクトロニクス業界にあります
All of your animations have gone through
あなたのアニメーションはすべて完了しました
Because of organic electronics, organic electronics just means that organic matter can emit light and generate electricity
有機エレクトロニクスですから、有機エレクトロニクスとは、単に有機物が発光し、電気を生成することを意味します。
Conducts electricity, but how does it become a product?
電気は通しますが、どうやって製品になるのでしょうか？
I don't know, so the first product is called OLED
分からないので、最初の製品はOLEDと呼ばれます
The second product is called OTFT, but OTFT is dead
2 番目の製品は OTFT と呼ばれていますが、OTFT は廃止されました
OTFT has been beaten to death by GRAPHIN
OTFTはGRAPHINに撲殺された
was beaten to death by Deputy Zhou
周副官に撲殺された
Then OLED, the second is OLED
次にOLED、2番目がOLEDです
Next up now is OPV
次はOPVです
this is what everyone is doing
これは誰もがやっていることです
But in the industry, in fact, sometimes we talk to business people
しかし、業界では実際、ビジネスマンと話をすることがあります。
The business world actually cares just to say
ビジネスの世界は実際にこう言うことだけを気にしています
In fact, to put it simply, it is a popular saying in the past.
実は簡単に言うと、昔よく言われた言葉なんです。
black cat, white cat, whatever your cat is
黒猫、白猫、どんな猫でも
A cat that catches mice is a good cat
ネズミを捕まえる猫は良い猫だ
TV is TV
テレビはテレビだ
From a
から
from the customer's point of view
顧客の視点から
He doesn't care at all it's an OLED TV
有機ELテレビだけど全然気にしてない
This is an LCD TV
これは液晶テレビです
This is CRD TV
こちらはCRDテレビです
what he wants is this thing
彼が欲しいのはこれです
Performance
表現
So what we have to know now is
それで、私たちが今知るべきことは、
identify where is the problem
問題がどこにあるのかを特定する
For example, heavy femoral nerve is a problem
たとえば、大腿神経が重いことが問題になります。
This platform can solve
このプラットフォームが解決できるのは、
Then this part we have to go through the doctor
次に、この部分は医師に相談する必要があります
Because only a doctor can tell us
医者にしか教えられないから
this problem
この問題
Is it possible for our platform to solve
私たちのプラットフォームで解決できるでしょうか
So the first step I think we still have to cooperate with the doctor
最初のステップとしては、やはり医師と協力する必要があると思います
academically
学術的に
Because academically you have not solved
学問的には解決してないから
Before determining what problems you can solve
どのような問題を解決できるかを判断する前に
Let's talk about mass production first
まずは量産について話しましょう
the first is
一つ目は
no one will
誰もしません
Talk to you about mass production
量産についてもご相談ください
because you can't go without him
彼なしではやっていけないから
Predict where your market is
市場がどこにあるのかを予測する
where is your market
あなたの市場はどこですか
The second question is
2番目の質問は、
he is not willing
彼はその気がない
risk him
彼を危険にさらす
In this respect, I believe
この点に関して、私はこう信じています
I'm sorry I talked a little bit more
ごめんなさい、もう少し話しました
Because I actually have quite a lot of experience
実はかなり経験豊富なので
that is to say in the United States
つまりアメリカでは
They use the so-called SBIR System
彼らはいわゆるSBIRシステムを使用しています
Lets you teach yourself how to start a company
会社の設立方法を独学で学べます
go after your dreams
あなたの夢を追い続けてください
So this is actually for me
つまり、これは実際に私のためのものです
I think it's a good
良いと思います
So Taiwan also has the SBIR System
台湾にもSBIRシステムがある
So instead of such a
したがって、そのような代わりに
that is
あれは
SBIR is a small company that invites professors
SBIRは教授を招聘する小さな会社です
put his help to this small company
この小さな会社に彼の手を貸してください
Just cooperate with his students to do a simple calculation
生徒たちと協力して簡単な計算をするだけです
That actually still uses Science
それは実際にはまだ科学を使用しています
Or a way for Technology to Push
あるいはテクノロジーが推進する方法
In fact, there are different models of development companies
実際、開発会社にはさまざまなモデルがあります
I don't think it's too early to go now
今から行くのに早すぎるとは思わない
identify partner
パートナーを特定する
but i think
しかし、私は思います
Our biggest problem right now is
私たちの今の最大の問題は、
identify where is the question
質問がどこにあるのかを特定する
is where is the question
質問はどこですか
If so, we can use this platform
もしそうなら、このプラットフォームを使用できます
Questions that can help
役立つ質問
We are actually cooperating with many hospitals now
現在、多くの病院と連携しています
go in a different direction
違う方向に行く
But I'm sorry we're not doing stock gods
でも、申し訳ありませんが、私たちは株の神様をやっているわけではありません
but we do something else
しかし、私たちは何か他のことをします
Because I didn't talk about our other topic today
今日は別の話題について話さなかったので
In fact, I am very passionate about this topic.
実際、私はこのテーマに非常に情熱を持っています。
But we have some other research topics that are
しかし、他にもいくつかの研究テーマがあります。
I was talking to the hospital, I actually got into it
病院に相談して、実際に入院しました
Nearly doing a stage of Proven Solving
もうすぐ実証済み解決の段階に到達します
But we are not doing Proven Solving now
しかし、現在は実証済み解決を行っていません
On this platform, we are just doing a pure academic discussion
このプラットフォームでは純粋に学術的な議論を行っているだけです
I don't think we have reached the stage of Proven Solving now
現在は実証済み解決の段階に達していないと思います
but we are
しかし私たちは
right
右
so i'm here i can't tell you
だから私はここにいる、あなたには言えない
which one are we now
私たちは今どちらですか
There's no way to tell you how we're going to have one
どのようにしてそれを手に入れるのかを伝える方法はありません
It's a business plan
事業計画書です
a business plan
一個business plan
just don't know where the problem is
ただ問題がどこにあるのかわからない
I think the question is very important
その質問はとても重要だと思います
you need to know where your problem is
問題がどこにあるのかを知る必要がある
Let me ask you this
これを聞いてみましょう
This New Rain will Out-Growth
この新しい雨は成長を上回るでしょう
president so much
社長そんなに
Then he obviously has the expression of stimulating a certain gene.
すると明らかに、ある遺伝子を刺激しているような表情をしている。
So have you researched the expression of those genes?
それで、それらの遺伝子の発現を研究しましたか？
The reason I say this now is because
なぜ今こんなことを言うのかというと、
Because you are all talking about medicine now
だって今みんな薬の話をしてるから
In fact, Taiwan's biotechnology is still in the medical field
実は台湾のバイオテクノロジーは今でも医療分野で活躍している
because my face
私の法律が直面しているからです
Taiwan's laws and regulations are considered a bit too strict in the world
台湾の法律や規制は世界的に見て少し厳しすぎると考えられています
so sometimes it can be a bit difficult
だから時々それは少し難しいかもしれない
But some biotechnology is not necessarily directly related to medicine
しかし、一部のバイオテクノロジーは必ずしも医学に直接関係しているわけではありません
In fact, it might be faster to walk.
実際は歩いたほうが早いかもしれません。
Like this, if you use electrodes to stimulate cells
このように、電極を使って細胞を刺激すると
you talk about nerves now
あなたは今神経について話しています
But say something about the cells
しかし、細胞については何か言ってください
Because now Taiwan uses cells to produce protein
なぜなら、台湾は現在細胞を使ってタンパク質を生産しているからです。
For example, the production of vaccines
例えば、ワクチンの製造
or produce some therapeutic proteins
または治療用タンパク質を生成する
or therapeutic antibodies
または治療用抗体
In fact, the demand is quite high
実は需要がかなり高いんです
If your electrode stimulation can promote the expression of certain genes
電極刺激により特定の遺伝子の発現が促進される場合
Software can make the protein of a certain feature
ソフトウェアは特定の機能のタンパク質を作ることができます
Or genetically engineered proteins can be produced in large quantities
あるいは、遺伝子組み換えタンパク質を大量に生産できる
I look back now to say
今振り返って言うと
Because what you see now is Alkose of cells
今見えているのは細胞のアルコースだから
A bunch behind Alkose
アルコセの後ろに大勢いる
There must be a large number of expression of genes
遺伝子の発現量が多いに違いない
If the performance can be stimulated by this electric shock
この電気ショックで演奏を刺激できれば
Maybe it's another way
もしかしたら別の方法かもしれない
It doesn't have to be superficial
表面的である必要はない
this and that
あれこれ
very considerate
とても思いやりのある
I know
知っている
thank you very much for this
どうもありがとうございました
This is actually a question I just answered
これは実際に私がたった今答えた質問です
we need to know
私たちは知る必要がある
where are the possibilities
可能性はどこにあるのか
This actually gives us a very good suggestion that
これは実際、次のような非常に良い示唆を与えてくれます。
it may be a possibility
それは可能性かもしれない
then i
その後私は
i'm sorry
ごめんなさい
I didn't make this truth very clear.
私はこの真実をあまり明確にしませんでした。
on this side
こちら側で
rightmost image
一番右の画像
In fact, in addition to stimulating cell growth, our TV sets
実際、私たちのテレビは細胞の成長を刺激するだけでなく、
because at that time hair
なぜならその時の髪は
To be honest it was because at that time
正直に言うと、あの時だったから
When you want to submit a question here
質問したいときはこちら
that
それか
Censor says you can't just demo water your TV cell growth
検閲官は、テレビの細胞の成長にただ水を注ぐだけではいけないと言う
You want demo water the second thing
次に必要なのはデモウォーターです
So without demo water the second thing is
デモウォーターがなければ、次のことは
It electrically stimulates protein secretion
電気的にタンパク質の分泌を刺激します
This protein is actually New on Gross Factor
このプロテインは実はグロスファクターの新製品です
it is at
それはです
Everyone I have studied New on Gross Factor
グロスファクターについて新しく勉強した人全員
New on Gross Factor
グロスファクターの新機能
The general New Long Long also has something called Shuang Cell
一般的なニューロンロンにはShuang Cellというものもあります
It is used to protect the cells of New Long
ニューロングの細胞を保護するために使用されます。
It itself secretes New Long Gloss Factor
それ自体が新しいロンググロスファクターを分泌します
Will help the New Long inside grow
内側のニューロングの成長を助けます
when we discovered the world of television
私たちがテレビの世界を発見したとき
Not only does it stimulate the growth of cells inside
内部の細胞の成長を刺激するだけでなく、
It also irritates the outer protective membrane
外側の保護膜も刺激します
To secrete more New Long Gloss Factor
新ロンググロスファクターをより多く分泌するには
I believe
私は信じている
you are right
あなたが正しいです
what is the first DNA
最初のDNAは何ですか
Actually more basic
実はもっと基本的なもの
we are doing now
私たちは今やっています
What exactly is Pathway
パスウェイとは正確には何ですか
Which Pathway is it?
どの経路ですか?
Because of
なぜなら
Adhesion Induced Pathway
癒着誘発経路
Or does it have another Pathway
それとも別の経路があるのでしょうか
we just did
私たちはたった今やったばかりです
We just did a little bit of proof
ちょっとした証明をしただけです
we did an experiment
私たちは実験をしました
we prove that
私たちはそれを証明します
It has nothing to do with Adhesion
粘着力とか関係ないよ
because when we use a drug
なぜなら、薬物を使用するときは
When living in the Adhesion Receptor Pathway Block
接着受容体経路ブロック内に居住している場合
TV still stimulates cell growth
テレビは依然として細胞の成長を刺激します
So the Machining of the TV
そこでテレビの加工
Growth-stimulating Machining
刺激生長的Machining
Pathway's Adhesion has nothing to do with it
経路の接着力は関係ありません
We have done this experiment
私たちはこの実験を行いました
because we didn't show it here
ここでは見せていないので
But we have done this experiment
しかし、私たちはこの実験を行ったのです
so i want your suggestion
だからあなたの提案が欲しいです
It's really precious, it's really nice
本当に貴重です、本当に良いです。
I do
そうです
If there is an actual
実物があれば
direction what we can do
私たちができることの方向性
we can also discuss
話し合うこともできます
because I've always felt that
ずっとそう感じていたから
That's right, just say
そうだよ、言ってみろよ
It's like I just re-emphasized to you
もう一度強調したような気がします
this is a platform
これはプラットフォームです
We have many possibilities
私たちにはたくさんの可能性があります
In fact, I should think
実際、私は考えるべきです
Because I told you this experiment arranged your experiment
この実験があなたの実験をアレンジしたと言いましたから
So you should be worth analyzing that transcript
したがって、その記録を分析する価値があるはずです
is all transcription
すべて転写です
It can be produced under the tube type
チューブタイプでも製作可能です
can you find it out
見つけられますか
So which specific genes are overexpressed?
では、どの特定の遺伝子が過剰発現するのでしょうか?
With and without batteries
電池の有無
you can compare
比較できます
If you compare, you will know which type of promoter
比べてみるとプロモーターの種類が分かります
may be particularly stimulated
特に刺激されるかもしれない
So that place is a
ですから、その場所は、
specific research pathway
具体的な研究経路
Thanks
ありがとう
today
今日
i didn't hear very clearly
あまりはっきり聞こえませんでした
My guess is you tried Top Down
トップダウンを試したのではないかと思います
do bionics again
またバイオニクスをやる
Do Modern Design again
モダンデザインをもう一度やる
Top Down
トップダウン
is you now identify the problem
あなたは今問題を特定していますか
Then analyze the mechanism inside
そして内部の仕組みを解析してみる
The basic elements inside
内部の基本要素
Now many are button up
今では多くの人がボタンを留めています
button up can't go far
ボタンを上げても遠くには行けない
Especially if you want to do Bio-Memetic
特にバイオミームをやりたい場合は
May have to do Top Down
トップダウンでやる必要があるかもしれない
ok
Ok
Thanks
ありがとう
actually for me
実は私にとって
I am not very sure
よくわかりません
sorry
ごめん
For me, Top Down and bottom up are Nano Science
私にとって、トップダウンとボトムアップはナノサイエンスです
For me those two words are Nano Science
私にとってこの 2 つの言葉はナノサイエンスです
we are using
私たちは使っています
but it doesn't matter
でもそれは関係ない
I probably know what you mean
おそらくあなたが言いたいことは分かります
i want to be in bio
バイオに入りたい
I think it's also possible that everyone knows
もしかしたら皆さんもご存知かと思いますが、
everyone may do too
みんなもそうするかもしれない
There are many ancestors who are living creatures who know that
それを知っている生き物のご先祖様はたくさんいます。
The biggest problem with being a creature is that you have to identify the waste problem
生物であることの最大の問題は、廃棄物の問題を特定しなければならないことだ
So all I can say is we have the system now
だから私に言えるのは、私たちは今そのシステムを持っているということだけだ
Then our system we Demonstrate a problem that is
次に、私たちのシステムが問題を実証します。
In fact, electromechanical cell growth
実際、電気機械セルの成長
how to make it faster
どうやって速くするか
this we did now
これは私たちが今やったことです
Then we can do it by changing the molecular structure
分子構造を変えることでそれが可能になります
that if
もし
Do you think this is called top down
これをトップダウンと言うのでしょうか？
Then I think it is top down
それならトップダウンだと思います
Because I'm actually not sure if this is called top down
これをトップダウンと呼ぶかどうかは実際にはわかりませんが、
but it does
しかし、それはあります
Toggy or question is whether there is a problem
トギーか質問は問題があるかどうか
Then how do we solve it
ではどうやって解決すればいいのか
i think this is
これだと思います
what we do all the time
私たちがいつもしていること
hope to be able to do
できることを願っています
The button up of Top down is on that
トップダウンのボタンアップはその上にあります
Nanotechnology
ナノテクノロジー
is a very ordinary management
ごく普通の経営です
Yeah
うん
It's top down, it's resography
それはトップダウン、それは再編集です
button up is self assembly
ボタンアップは組み立て式です
For us, top down is resography
私たちにとってトップダウンはリソグラフィーです
then my simplest
それから私の最も単純な
i will sit on the plane
私は飛行機に座ります
I will divide it on the top down
上から下に分けていきます
Molecule atoms made later
後で作られた分子原子
Button up is done from the molecular atom to the top
ボタンアップは分子原子から上に向かって行われます
OK
OK
OK, is there any more?
はい、まだありますか?
well behind
かなり遅れて
Hello doctor, I am a college student in the Department of Biotechnology
こんにちは、先生、私はバイオテクノロジー学科の大学生です。
That may not work, the problem may not be so professional theory
それはうまくいかないかもしれない、問題はそれほど専門的な理論ではないかもしれない
Yes, then what I want to ask is because your experiment is about electrical stimulation of cells
はい、それでは私が聞きたいのは、あなたの実験は細胞の電気刺激に関するものだからです
The Xianbai just now also mentioned that because it stimulates cell growth
先ほどの仙白さんも、細胞の成長を刺激するからだとおっしゃっていました。
We know that there may be many proteins in the cell
細胞内には多くのタンパク質が存在する可能性があることがわかっています
So can we just focus on certain proteins
では、特定のタンパク質だけに焦点を当ててもよいでしょうか
or destimulate on certain transfer factors
または特定の伝達係数を非刺激化する
Or send out some message for the receptors to pick up
または、受信者が受信できるようにメッセージを送信します。
thereby deactivating those proteases and the like
それによってそれらのプロテアーゼなどを不活性化する
Yes, maybe, not the whole cell
はい、おそらく、細胞全体ではありません
Maybe it's part of the genes or something like the uprightness of the cells
おそらくそれは遺伝子の一部か、細胞の直立性のようなものかもしれません
It can be stimulated without shortening too quickly
短くしすぎずに刺激できる
or
また
to enable the cell to prolong its lifespan and things like that
細胞の寿命を延ばすなどのことを可能にする
That is, the possible research directions are more professional and more
つまり、考えられる研究の方向性は、より専門的で、より高度なものになります。
The range is a bit smaller, but not that big
範囲は少し狭いですが、それほど大きくはありません
Just let the cells grow
あとは細胞を増殖させるだけ
Is it possible to do research on this
これについて研究することは可能ですか
That question is actually very good
その質問は実に良い質問です
Don't worry
心配しないで
because we are here
私たちはここにいるから
Just to share with you our experiments
私たちの実験を皆さんと共有したいと思います
what you just said
あなたが今言ったこと
absolutely right
絶対的に正しい
because in fact
なぜなら実際には
The simplest matter of light cell growth
光細胞の成長に関する最も単純な問題
actually a
実際には
in biomedicine
生物医学において
actually a very important thing
実はとても大切なこと
Because actually I
なぜなら、実際に私は
Although protein analysis
タンパク質の分析ですが、
do genetic analysis
遺伝子解析をする
It is very important in education
教育においてとても大切なことです
It is also very, very necessary to understand
それを理解することも非常に非常に必要です
Because knowing why is not just because
なぜなら、理由を知るということは、ただ単に理由を知るだけではないからです。
It's Santific fun
サンティフィック楽しいよ
but because
しかし理由は
Even if you go into that
そこに入っても
FDA
FDA
Even at the legal level
法律レベルでも
he needs you to know too
彼もあなたに知ってもらう必要があります
What is the mechanism behind any drug or device
薬物や装置の背後にあるメカニズムは何ですか
This is the pharmacological mechanism must be known
これは薬理学的メカニズムを知る必要があります
so it's all important
だからそれはすべて重要です
But I think one of the things we do is
しかし、私たちがやっている事の一つは、
What we often do is say
私たちがよくやるのはこう言うことです
we also want to say see
私たちも見てくださいと言いたいです
electrical stimulation
電刺激
Surface-bound receptor stimulation
表面結合受容体の刺激
Stimulation even combined with nanostructures
ナノ構造と組み合わせても刺激
Can we use the fastest way
最速の方法を使用できますか
to enhance cell growth
細胞の成長を促進する
This is actually very important in biomedicine
実はこれは生物医学において非常に重要です
Of course, the reason I say this is because
もちろん、なぜこんなことを言うのかというと、
Actually it has a market over there
実はそこに市場があるのです
Not only in research, you are very happy to save people
研究だけでなく、人を救うことにとても喜びを感じますね
And it does have a market over there
そしてそこには市場があります
In fact, what many people in this market are doing is
実際、この市場の多くの人がやっていることは、
Includes sports medicine
スポーツ医学も含まれる
Sports medicine
スポーツ医学
how do you make a person
どうやって人を作るのですか
today i thought i would give a
今日はあげようと思った
Because today is the enjoyment of knowledge, I will lift it up
今日は知識の楽しみだから持ち上げるよ
relatively simple
比較的単純な
For example, now the NBA final
たとえば、今のNBAファイナルでは、
Everyone knows that the NBA is playing the finals now
NBAが今決勝戦を行っていることは誰もが知っています
If today is unlucky
もし今日が不運だったら
Lobrom James
ロブロム・ジェームス
broken foot
骨折した足
If you can get him back in a week
一週間以内に彼を取り戻せたら
can he get you back
彼はあなたを取り戻してもらえますか
1 million US dollars
100万米ドル
he must be willing
彼は喜んでいるに違いない
but you have to be good
しかし、あなたは良くなければなりません
that is how we are
それが私たちです
biologically listen to you
生物学的にあなたの言うことを聞いてください
If we use these stimuli appropriately
これらの刺激を適切に使えば
to stimulate cell growth
細胞の成長を刺激する
absolutely very important
絶対にとても重要
so i believe
だから私は信じます
what i said to you is not wrong
私があなたに言ったことは間違っていません
we have done
終わりました
we noticed
私たちは気づきました
Electrical stimulation coupled with stimulation of surface structures
表面構造の刺激と組み合わせた電気刺激
Both have additive effects
どちらも相加効果がある
Can make cells grow faster
細胞の成長を早めることができる
Include
含む
so-called copying
いわゆるコピー
That is, the speed of proliferation will become faster
つまり、普及のスピードが速くなるということです
But the proliferation is over
但是proliferation完了
You have to make sure the cells are all good
細胞がすべて正常であることを確認する必要があります
Then we have to do another experiment on this part.
次に、この部分について別の実験を行う必要があります。
but i think
しかし、私は思います
this thing means
このことの意味は
biomedical aspects
生物医学的側面
bioelectronics
バイオエレクトロニクス
organic bioelectronics
有機バイオエレクトロニクス
The hardest thing is because you have to integrate
最も難しいのは、統合する必要があるためです
From Upstream to Downstream Upstream Material Design
上流から下流へ 上流のマテリアルデザイン
Midstream Engineering Design
中流エンジニアリング設計
and then to downstream medical applications
そして下流の医療アプリケーションへ
It all comes together so
すべてがひとつに集まってきているので、
sometimes we look like we
時々私たちは私たちのように見える
We are a little more scattered now, we don’t have folks talking about which parts are done very carefully
今はもう少し分散していますが、すべての部分が非常に慎重に行われていると言える人はいません
We hope to put such a situation first
私たちはそのような状況を第一に考えたいと考えています
were able
できた
Explain to everyone, you can do a simple Demonstration
みんなに説明してください、簡単なデモンストレーションができます
in this way
この上
there are still problems
まだ問題があります
that because i do
それは私がそうするからです
IC packet analysis, so we all know
ICパケット解析だからみんな知ってる
IC package is because in terms of transfer or transfer
ICパッケージは転送または転送の観点から
may have gone wrong and produced
間違って生成された可能性があります
are bad cells, or tumors as they're commonly known.
一般に知られている不良細胞、または腫瘍です。
Is it possible to use electrodes to stimulate and make it
電極を使って刺激して作ることは可能ですか？
wrong turn into right
間違ったものが正しいものに変わる
Then proceed to produce normal cells
その後、正常な細胞の生成に進みます
can then replace the original abnormal cells
元の異常な細胞を置き換えることができます
this...
これ...
No, I think the idea is very creative
いいえ、そのアイデアはとてもクリエイティブだと思います
but i really...
でも私は本当に...
Sorry, I can't answer because I'm not a doctor
申し訳ありませんが、私は医師ではないのでお答えできません
Perhaps some doctors have done such an experiment
もしかしたら、そのような実験をした医師もいるかもしれません
He will tell you if this is possible
それが可能かどうか彼は教えてくれるでしょう
Because sometimes I won't tell you right away that it's not possible
時々、それは不可能だとすぐには言わないから
because actually many things
なぜなら実際には多くのことが
because sometimes there are things that just don't have the right material to do it
時々、それを行うのに適切な素材がないことがあるからです
The problem we often find when we make materials is
資料を作るときによくある問題は、
Some people have some wrong ideas before because there was no proper material before
以前は適切な資料がなかったため、間違った考えを持っている人もいます
Now that there are appropriate materials, is it possible to do such a thing?
適切な材料が揃った今、そのようなことは可能でしょうか？
Maybe you can try again
もう一度試してみてもいいかもしれません
But so far we haven't been doing this.
しかし、これまでのところ、私たちはこれを行っていません。
We've never heard a doctor tell us that there's such a possibility.
医者がそのような可能性があると言ったのを聞いたことがありません。
But I guess it's an idea
でもアイデアだと思うよ
You can try to find literature
文献を探してみることができます
see if anyone does
誰かがそうするかどうか見てください
If you find warmth and are interested
温もりを感じて興味を持っていただけたら
Our middle school has its own program, including a PhD program
私たちの中学校には博士課程を含む独自のプログラムがあります
There are all kinds of programs, we welcome you to come
様々なプログラムをご用意しておりますので、ぜひお越しください
thank you doctor
ありがとう博士
Do you have other people's questions?
他の人の質問はありますか？
I want to ask you a question
質問があります
I see you've done a great job on the side of NPT
NPT側で素晴らしい仕事をしてくれたことがわかります
Then you also answered some key questions about creating potential changes
次に、潜在的な変化の創出に関するいくつかの重要な質問にも答えました
But I think whether it's in our biological or medical part
しかし、それが生物学的部分であろうと医学的部分であろうと私は思います
In fact, everyone is more familiar
実際には、誰もがもっとよく知っています
I think it is useful for living things
生き物にとっては役に立つと思うよ
is the increase or decrease in the expression of its protein
そのタンパク質の発現の増加または減少です
I think that's probably why when you submit
投稿するときはおそらくそれが原因だと思います
will be subject to some responses
何らかの対応が必要となります
So my question is
それで私の質問は
Parts for these BioSensor
このバイオセンサーの部品
How to use electrical signal to detect in...
電気信号を使って検出する方法
any target, such as a limited change in a protein in a nerve cell
神経細胞内のタンパク質の限定的な変化など、任意の標的
Is there such a way?
そんな方法はあるのでしょうか？
i think this question
私はこの質問を思う
In fact, my questions today are very good, I like it very much
実際、今日の私の質問はとても良いもので、とても気に入っています。
Actually what you mentioned is that I just mentioned
実際、あなたが言及したことは、私がちょうど言及したことです
I just gave you a simple hint
簡単なヒントを教えただけです
That is to say, the guide polymer
つまりガイドポリマー
The guide polymer itself has a very good function, which is
ガイドポリマー自体は非常に優れた機能を持っており、
Excuse me
すみません
OK
OK
One of the biggest functions of guiding polymers is to use them as biological detectors
ガイドポリマーの最大の機能の 1 つは、ガイドポリマーを生物学的検出器として使用することです。
Why can he be a biodetector? Because it's simple
なぜ彼は生体検出器になれるのでしょうか? それは単純だからです
You just saw that we can do molecular modification, right?
分子修飾ができることはわかりましたよね?
I'm sorry, let me run another one to try love
ごめんなさい、愛を試すためにもう一つ実行させてください
you can do molecular modification
分子修飾ができる
After molecular modification
分子修飾後
I can easily pick some on it
いくつか簡単に接続できます
Next up is Leaghan
次はリーガンです
Get something to detect
検出するものを取得する
Then the conduction below you is an electrical signal
あなたの下の伝導は電気信号です
with a Leaghan on it
リーガンが乗っている
So when any organism comes
だから、どんな生物が来ても
When creating a Binding with this Leaghan
このリーガンでバインディングを作成する場合
It may affect the transmission of electrical signals below
以下の電気信号の伝達に影響を与える可能性があります。
you create a difference in electrical signal
電気信号に違いを生み出します
This electrical signal can then be used as a biometric sensor
この電気信号は生体認証センサーとして使用できます。
So we're doing something like this
そこで私たちは次のようなことをしています
just because of today's time
今日の時間のせいで
I probably can't tell you all the results of 10 years
10年間の結果をすべて語ることはおそらくできない
I only gave two examples
例を 2 つだけ挙げました
But you said biometric sensors are really important
でも生体センサーは本当に重要だと言いましたね
And that's actually in the conductive polymer
それは実際には導電性ポリマーの中にあります
It's what everyone was doing in the first place.
それは最初から誰もがやっていることです。
In the early days, everyone came to make biological detectors.
初期の頃は、誰もが生物学的検出器を作るためにやって来ました。
Because biometric sensors are very important
生体センサーは非常に重要なので
We're relatively not doing biometric detection ourselves right now.
現在、私たち自身では生体認証の検出をあまり行っていません。
But many of the things we're doing
しかし、私たちが行っていることの多くは、
We are catching, in addition to organic electro-shock materials, we also have a large branch to capture the so-called circulating cancer cells
私たちは、有機電気ショック材料に加えて、いわゆる循環がん細胞を捕捉するための大きなブランチも備えています。
But we start with another big piece, about 40% to 50% of the research is in that direction
しかし、私たちは別の大きな部分から始めます。研究の約 40% ～ 50% はその方向にあります。
So these two pieces are actually very big. I just mentioned a little bit about our first three pieces: Bioimaging, Biodetection, and Bioelectronic
この 2 つの部分は実際には非常に大きなもので、最初の 3 つの部分、バイオイメージング、バイオ検出、バイオエレクトロニクスについては先ほど少し触れました。
This part is about biological detection, including how we understand the mutation of cancer cells. We are doing this part.
この部分は、がん細胞の変異をどのように理解するかを含む生物学的検出に関する部分であり、私たちはこの部分を行っています。
if
もしも
We are at the action, we can see that you can do accenture, actuator, how is the actuator doing now?
アクチュエーター、アクチュエーターは今どうなっているのですか?
The actuator is actually no, not now, and it is not doing it now, because the actuator is not doing it because of the lack of human resources.
アクチュエーターは実は、いや、今はやっていないんです、人材不足でアクチュエーターがやっていないんです。
actuator is
アクチュエーターは
It's not us, in fact, we are the other way around.
それは私たちではありません、実際、私たちはその逆なのです。
I think we are doing the more difficult
私たちはもっと難しいことをやっていると思います
because we feel that saying
私たちはその言葉を感じているからです
Since there are such resources
そういったリソースがあるので、
It seems like we should be doing some comparisons
いくつかの比較を行う必要があるようです
to challenge something more difficult
もっと難しいことに挑戦する
I don't think we're doing simple
私たちがやっていることは単純ではないと思います
Instead feel
代わりに感じてください
Sometimes our lab sometimes complains to me that we are doing difficult things
時々、私たちの研究室は、難しいことをやっていると私に文句を言うことがあります。
last question
最後一個問題
Hello, I am
こんにちは私は
this speech is very good
このスピーチはとても良いです
Just now I
たった今私は
The informant mentioned that
情報提供者はこう述べた
Part of X-rayter
X-rayter的部分
I'm curious to say
言いたいのですが
when this vibration
この振動のとき
it is this
これです
Its tension is similar to this part of their way to achieve the limit of human beings
この部分の緊張感は人間の限界に似ています。
The way they say if it's doing the same as the limit
限界と同じことをしているかどうかを彼らが言う方法
they are likely to do
彼らはそうする可能性が高い
Increase
増加
That is to say, in the experiment, let some people
つまり、実験で何人かの人々に
Insufficient grip strength
握力不足
or his
または彼の
If they can't stand up, they can do it
彼らが立ち上がれないなら、彼らはそれをすることができます
Enhance the human body ability to this part
この部分の人体の能力を強化します
It's just like being curious that he can follow
彼がフォローできるかどうか興味があるようなものです
Bio-chamber mixed
混合バイオチャンバー
Uh uh this is not exclusion
ああ、これは除外ではありません
OK
OK
Yes, let's go
はい、行きましょう
I should prepare a hundred slimes today
今日はスライムを100個用意しなきゃ
Because I have Sly
スライがいるから
But I'm now Sly in the computer
でも私は今、コンピューターの中のスライです
It might take a lot of time if I'm driving
車だとかなり時間がかかるかも
I'll simply answer your question
あなたの質問に簡単に答えます
so we say
だから私たちは言います
it actually
それは実際に
This x-ray is right
このレントゲンは正しいです
The so-called x-ray thing, I actually did some when I was in my doctoral class
いわゆる X 線撮影については、博士課程のときに実際にいくつか撮影しました。
Then some of my former collaborators and I
それから私と私の元協力者たち
included in australia
オーストラリアに含まれる
This piece of x-ray is doing very well in Australia
このX線写真はオーストラリアで非常にうまくいっている
that's not you
それはあなたではありません
It's what we live for.
それが私たちが生きている理由なのです。
or how to actually x-ray
または実際にX線を撮影する方法
The performance of conduction to molecules is very good
分子への伝導性能が非常に優れています
very good
とても良い
just say
言うだけ
Just like what my classmate mentioned just now is
さっきクラスメイトが言っていたのと同じように、
Where is your market and how do you find mass production
市場はどこですか、大量生産はどのようにして見つけますか
That is the problem of commercial ratio
それは商業比率の問題です
that's a problem
それは問題だ
But on Santipi I think they did a very, very good job
でもサンティピでは彼らはとてもとても良い仕事をしたと思う
They learn some, of course they learn some very strange surrounds like what
彼らはいくつかを学びます、もちろん、彼らは次のような非常に奇妙な環境を学びます
They say, you want to see what's the use of putting it like this
彼らはこう言う、こんな風に置いて何の役に立つのか知りたいのね
They can make a fish, so that the fish can move by itself
彼らは魚を作ることができるので、魚はそれ自体で動くことができます
Or, in fact, when I was in BHD, I also received
実際、私も BHD にいたときに、
We actually have pick up some of this like
実際にこのようなものをいくつかピックアップしました
Robot's Project
ロボットのプロジェクト
In fact, for robots, Actualator is very useful for robots
実際、ロボットにとって Actualator は非常に便利です
Because if you think about it, robots now use mechanical methods to do things
考えてみれば、ロボットは現在、機械的な方法を使って物事を行っているからです。
The mechanical way is from metal material, so the weight is very heavy
機械式は金属材料を使用しているため、重量は非常に重いです
What they want is that if I change the mechanical way into the material way
彼らが望んでいるのは、もし私が機械的な方法を物質的な方法に変えたら、ということです
In the way of Actualator, it's like you put ligaments on your robotic arm
Actualator で言えば、ロボットアームに靭帯を付けるようなものです
He hopes that the Actualator is like a ligament, a soft substance
彼は、このアクチュエータが靭帯のような、柔らかい物質であることを望んでいます。
It means that his idea comes from saying that the arm of a robot must have soft matter
つまり、彼のアイデアはロボットの腕には柔らかい物質がなければならないということから来ているということです
Instead of using mechanical means to move the joints
関節を動かすために機械的手段を使用する代わりに
Instead, the articulation is done in a material way
代わりに、表現は物質的な方法で行われます
They hope to achieve lightweight
彼らは軽量化を達成したいと考えています
Of course, this stock has been doing it back then
もちろん、この株は当時からやっています
But because I really didn't do it now
でも今は本当にやってないから
So I'm not quite sure where the newest has made it now
したがって、最新のものが今どこに到達しているのかはよくわかりません
Early in about my time
私の頃の早い段階で
In the early 2000s
2000年代初頭
I think it is a very popular feel
とても人気のある感じだと思います
at the end make a
最後に、を作ります
There is one here
ここに 1 つあります
It's a question I really want to ask, isn't it?
それは本当に聞きたい質問ですよね。
right
右
microphone
マイクロフォン
Excuse me
すみません
hello i am a general public
こんにちは、私は一般人です
I would like to ask some doctors for their views on the so-called 2045 plan
いわゆる2045年計画について何人かの医師の意見を聞きたいです。
news on the internet
インターネット上のニュース
I don't know if it's true or it will come true
本当かどうかは分からない、現実になるかどうかは分からない
It's like the idea in the Avatar movie.
映画『アバター』のアイデアに似ています。
First from the human will to control the machine and then
まず機械を制御するという人間の意志から、そして
Make life more possible
生活をより可能にする
it's ok i want this stuff
大丈夫、これが欲しいんだ
i never
私は決して
do not do any negation
否定はしないでください
Neither do I, but I can't make any affirmations with you
私もそうは思わないが、あなたに肯定することはできない
Sorry, this is so far
申し訳ありませんが、ここまでです
We focus on the academics of Science
私たちは科学の学術に焦点を当てています
Um
えーっと
don't be like i said
私が言ったようにならないでください
Well, the Science I told you at the beginning is
さて、冒頭でお話しした科学とは、
Hollywood is great
ハリウッドってすごいよな
they can
彼らはできます
tell us many ways
いろいろ教えてください
but our own words
でも私たち自身の言葉
we will feel academic
私たちは学術的な気分になるでしょう
come to see for ourselves
自分たちで見に来てください
We used to think Alphabuy was impossible
私たちはAlphabuyは不可能だと思っていました
but now you can
でも今ならできる
I never said no
私は決してノーとは言わなかった
but I cannot say yes right now
でも今は「はい」とは言えません
Someone thought about it before
前に誰かが考えた
It's just that computers aren't fast enough
ただコンピューターの速度が足りないだけです
The computer is not fast enough now
コンピューターの速度が十分ではありません
The computer is fast enough now
今のコンピュータは十分に速いです
that is
あれは
just right
ちょうどいい
so i think
だから私は思う
Such a wonderful speech today
今日はとても素晴らしいスピーチでした
I make a quick summary
簡単にまとめてみます
Because Academia Sinica
中央研究院だから
What we do is basic research
私たちがやっているのは基礎研究です
just like this time
今回と同じように
Boss mentioned this to us
ボスが私たちにこのことを言いました
Conductive
導電的
After the new material of organic polymer comes out
有機高分子という新素材が出てきてから
Then we can find that it can be compared with biological cells
そうすれば、それが生体細胞と比較できることがわかります
Many things in living organisms can be done very effectively
生物の多くのことは非常に効率的に行うことができます
then unbroken binding
それから壊れない結合
So we can use the outside world to conduct electricity
つまり、外界を利用して電気を流すことができるのです
with current
用電流
Then go talk to creatures and change some creatures inside
次に、生き物に話しかけて、中の生き物をいくつか変更します
or one of some of its functions
またはその機能の一部
Go can do some conversion or do some sides
Go はいくつかの変換やいくつかの側面を行うことができます
After all, there are still many, many, many possibilities for the application behind this.
結局のところ、この背後にはアプリケーションの可能性がまだたくさんあります。
So its whole breaking point is in that one
つまり、その限界点はまさにそこにある
conductive polymer
導電高分子
that
それか
It is the whole discovery of conducting polymer
それは導電性高分子の発見のすべてです
This is a
これは
a jumping one
ジャンプするもの
A Progressive Advancement in Academics
学術における漸進的な進歩
So under this basic research
したがって、この基礎研究の下では
For this thing in the future
今後のこの事に関しては
where will it go
どこへ行くのでしょう
We all don't know the truth now
今はみんな本当のことは分からない
so today again
それで今日もまた
That Dr. You gave us some direction
博士が私たちに指示を与えてくれたこと
Those directions are the ones that are going on now.
それらの方向性が現在進行中のものです。
So just had some very practical questions
非常に実践的な質問がいくつかありました
Is it possible to do this
これは可能ですか
Can you do that back to the end?
最後までやってもらえますか？
What are the details of the impact it will have afterwards?
その後の影響は具体的にどうなっているのでしょうか？
I think this is what we have to do in scientific research now
これが今科学研究でやらなければならないことだと思います
because everyone knows
誰もが知っているから
We now your laser is better than this thing
今ではあなたのレーザーの方がこれよりも優れています
lasers are everywhere
レーザーはどこにでもあります
When the laser came out
レーザーが出てきたら
It's just that there are two conversions that can be connected inside.
ただ、内部で接続できる変換が2つあるだけです。
So when I found that
それでそれを見つけたとき
It never occurred to me that lasers can now be used as scalpels
レーザーがメスとして使えるようになるなんて思いもしませんでした
can do your music can save
音楽を保存できます
it's all behind
すべては背中の問題です
So what we are doing in the hospital of traditional Chinese medicine is a kind of
ですから、私たちが伝統的な中国医学の病院で行っていることは、ある種のことです。
Very upstream basic research
基礎研究の最上流
We hope to be able to find some direction
何らかの方向性を見つけられることを願っています
Pad some ground
地面を埋めます
Find the one that can confirm which of these works
これらのどれが機能するかを調べてください
what other possible directions
他にどのような方向が考えられるか
Then there are many, many steps below
次に、以下に非常に多くの手順があります
this thing
このこと
Is it possible to mass produce
大量生産は可能ですか
Is it possible to go down
下がることは可能ですか
Of course, the people behind will come to relay.
もちろん後ろの人も中継に来ます。
So we are doing a lot of trying
だから私たちはたくさんの試みをしています
something will fail
何かが失敗するだろう
something will work out
何かがうまくいくだろう
I don't know this
これはわかりません
So now it's the work of doing these explorations
さて、これからはこれらの探索を行う作業です
Hope some people do upstream
誰かが上流でやってくれることを願っています
Some do midstream
途中でやる人もいる
Some say downstream
下流だと言う人もいる
string this thing up
これを紐でつなぐ
so today
それで今日
So some things may be more abstract
したがって、いくつかのことはより抽象的になる可能性があります
It's because of what we're doing now
それは私たちが今やっていることのせいです
yeah just look
はい、見てください
Are these things really useful?
これらは本当に役に立つのでしょうか？
always try something first
いつも最初に何かを試してみる
that tells the report
それはレポートに伝えます
Today's report is to tell you some
今日のレポートはその一部をお伝えするものです
progress in this area
この分野の進歩
that is maybe in a few years
それはもしかしたら数年以内かもしれない
we can stop
私たちは立ち止まることができる
It's not about coming back and looking again
戻ってまた見ないでください
is there something in five years
5年以内に何かある？
some new developments
いくつかの新しい展開
or you can download from
またはからダウンロードできます
some media reports
一部メディアの報道
if there are some new developments
何か新たな展開があれば
will also know
も分かるだろう
So today our knowledge
それで今日の私たちの知識は
want to
をしたい
This purpose is to tell you about some of the latest developments
この目的は、最新の開発状況についてお知らせすることです。
So that's the purpose of all today
それが今日の目的です
So before I wrap up I want to report back
それでは、最後に報告する前に報告したいと思います
Preview next month in May
来月5月にプレビュー
Knowledge Trial on May 23rd
5月23日のナレッジトライアル
We have another theme that is
もう一つの主題があります。
Genome Center
ゲノムセンター
Hong Shangcheng of Genome Research Center
ゲノム研究センターのホン・シャンチェン
Specific Researcher and Director
特定研究員・所長
Tell us about molecular blood
分子血液について教えてください
That fold is not a fold but a fold
その折り目は折り目ではなく折り目です
So it's another field
それは別の分野ですので
have another development
別の展開がある
is actually a molecule
実は分子です
but it's totally different
でもそれは全く違います
From another point of view
別の観点から見ると
I think today's time is also very tight
今日も時間は厳しいと思います
Then let's thank you at this time
それではこの度はお礼を言わせてください
Brilliant copy given to us by Dr. Xia Hua
夏華博士から贈られた素晴らしいコピー
thank you for the glory
栄光をありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
Cai GuoICE
蔡国ICE